Why are you crying?
Huh?
- Because my wrists hurt
-Do your tiny wrists hurt? Uh?
These hurt, uh?
You look like a hot dog
So, what have you learned?
-That I must obey you
-Why don’t you look at me when I’m talking to you
When I was younger, I didn’t want to hear anything about men
I had a special relationship with sex.
My sexual behavior wasn’t quite normal for my age.
People around me were too narrow-minded
Anything out of their point of view was wrong
I was wrong, actually
And I’m not saying I’m not
But they just never tried to understand the reasons behind my behavior
They couldn’t understand what the mind can do to overcome certain things
Our relationship started in a really strange way
We had known each other for a while but I didn’t know anything about his life
The first time we talked after a long time
I told him I wanted to try something that wasn’t new for him
Take off your shirt
What excites me the most is to feel I am his
I like it when he chokes me
When he hits me, spits on me, when he insults me
when he does with me whatever he wants
to be his possession
But to be his I needed a name
I am MIA
But I’m okay with that since I know I can trust him
I know he’s always going to protect me and would never hurt me
His own violence makes me feel safe
If I do whatever he asks for...
I’ll have what I want
- Master
I love you
- It's like cinnamon, the more you use, the worse it tastes
- I have never used it
- Ew gross! You stuffed your mouth with bread
- Why the fuck did you stick your finger in then?
When I do something wrong, I  get a punishment
Like when I’m late or forget my choker
Without the collar I can’t be MIA
The punishment is usually leaving me without sex
something I can't be without
So in order to be forgiven I beg for a lesson
To show him I deserve the special treatment.
- Are you sorry or what, fucking whore?
- Yes, Master
- What?
- Yes
What do you say? Uh?
- Thank you master
- That’s what I want to hear, whore
There’s no doubt. It’s clear to see
To me, imagination is everything
If you imagine something often enough, It will become real
It doesn't matter if it's not
Having a master is something I couldn’t explain
I guess people who have a master like me, they place them outside from their ordinary life
But me, I do it as a part of the intellectual connection I have with him
It's something special with someone who's special
Denying it would only bring me a life full of lies
I know for many MIA is a sign of repression
but for me is the beginning of my freedom
I’ve spend my whole life blaming myself for not fitting into society's standards
I feel like most people are pretending
I have built a relationship where I can be me
and share it with someone else
Such things happen when two different people get together, doesn't it?
You never know what’s going to happen
All of my sexual intercourses have always been a fucking mess
Even though I haven't had many
I don’t know why we all try so hard to be so similar to each other
- Won't you let me cook?
I’m talking to you
aren't you gonna let me cook?
Do you want to fuck?
Give me your panties
Not a single noise, okay?
Turn around
I feel like many things have changed
I brought to light something from me that was broken
The things from the past always hurt
and will never disappear It
is all in your attitude
- Do you want me to cum in your face?
whether you learn from them or let them become a burden
- Cum in my face, please
But it's not as easy when it comes to abuse
There’s no need to say much more
It always hurts to have no choice
Specially when it happens to you when you're four years old
- Here's your reward, whore
Do you like it?
MIA can only exist because it comes from a part of me that I enjoy
even though I know it’s not easy
- So, what do you say?
-Thank you, Master.
- That’s what I want to hear, MIA
I doubt there’s ever going to be another Master
- No, I want to lick your hand
This is something that was born here
and if it has to die
it will die here
- My little girl