(Totti) I think the first word that I could say was "football”.
In 1977, in Porto San Giorgio,
with all my cousins, uncles and aunts.
The sea, the beach, the games.
For me it was all new.
It was beautiful.
That's my mother.
This is my father.
This is me.
I was playing football.
What's in my mind is only to kick the ball around.
From there this all started.
(Man) Roma without Totti
is like a city without the sun.
(Man 2) The game is over.
They took the ball away from us.
(Man 3) I don't believe it.
If I must think about tomorrow, I prefer thinking about yesterday.
(Woman) For me this is Roma’s funeral.
For me, Roma dies here.
(Totti) I don't believe that I'm done.
Starting from tomorrow, I will no longer
wear my boots. No more jersey. Nothing.
It is not possible.
I have been here
for 25 years of my life.
Such memories.
(Carlo Zampa) Players are on him.
(Carlo Zampa) He shoots!
(CROWD NOISE)
- (Caressa) He got away.
- (Compagnoni) He’s looking for an opening.
(Caressa) He’s almost inside the penalty box!
- Totti !
- (Compagnoni) Missed it by a whisker!
(Caressa) Totti is free!
Pallonetto !
Totti !
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(Totti) Tomorrow will be the last time
I play as a professional footballer.
My name is Francesco Totti.
I am the captain of AS Roma.
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(Totti) In 1983, it had been 40 years
since Roma last won the Scudetto
"We were born to suffer", they say.
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(HORN)
(Totti) I was a little boy.
I remember the horns,
the noise, the flags.
Wherever you went,
there was chaos everywhere.
That summer, after school,
in the afternoon we always
gathered at Manzoni.
With me, there were
my brother Riccardo,
my cousin Angelo,
Antonio ‘the Dead’,
because he was white like a corpse,
then there was Bambino
the two Giancarlo: Giancarlo Ciccacci
and Giancarlo Pantano.
Our favorite game
was Paperelle (The Ducklings)
It’s a group of children
standing at the top of the ladder.
They started walking
one after another.
They went down the step
to the end of the ladder.
Below,a kid must kick the ball
and hit all these ‘ducks’.
Who hit the most ducks
won an ice cream.
I was small.
They never let me play.
One day, I persuaded them,
or maybe, I made them feel pity for me
Then they asked me: "Do you want to play ?"
In that moment, I thought of both
everything and nothing at once.
But I realized, when it was my turn,
the sound of the ball was different.
I kicked hard.
Hard and precise.
I kicked and hit a duck.
I kicked and hit another duck.
I took them all.
They couldn't believe it.
One day, my cousin Angelo told me:
"Let's go and have a trial
at Fortitudo Football School."
It was only a hundred meters from home.
We lived in Via Vetulonia.
I lived there with my father, my mother,
my brother, and my grandfather.
This was my little family.
As a child, I was very shy.
I was not socializing as I should have.
At school, I closed myself off.
However, with the excuse
that I am now a football player,
every now and then I hid
that problem behind.
Finally when I was ten years old,
I went to play for Lodigiani.
Lodigiani was already an important team.
It was Roma, Lazio, Lodigiani
Lodigiani was Rome's third team.
We said they're our city's second team,
because Roma is first, and then Lodigiani.
Lazio is the third.
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(Totti) During this time, my father and uncle
gave me 5000 Lira for every goal I scored.
In fact, I made them regret this.
I emptied their wallets!
My father never praised me.
My mother every now and then,
secretly, complimented me.
She is the one
I am most attached to.
My dad worked until late every day.
So she picked me up from school,
and took me to trainings,
She waited for me out there.
My parents saw a passion in me.
I cannot let go of football.
On Saturday, when everyone went out,
I stayed at home and slept.
I would sit there, and watch the games.
I drank a glass of cold milk
before going to bed.
In the morning at 7, I woke up.
I ate breakfast and went to training.
(Man) Go!
(Totti) Words got out
that there was this strong kid.
So much that the coach told me:
"Watch out, they will hurt you."
"Don't respond to them, watch out."
(Man) "Daje"!
(PROTESTING VOICES)
- (Woman) Fool!
- (Woman 2) Throw the ball out!
(Man 2) You are good!
(Totti) I was still a kid,
so I hadn’t  really thought about big things or my future.
But these are moments
that you hardly forget.
In 1989 the president of Lodigiani called me,
because both Roma and Lazio wanted me to play for them.
Being a family of Roma supporters,
it was impossible
to take another path.
If I had chosen Lazio, my family
would never spoke with me again!
The first time I was at Trigoria,
it was like a dream.
I was 12, 13 years old.
I walked in front the of training ground.
I saw the first team training.
I feel like the happiest kid in the world.
Seeing Giannini during training
was the best part of it.
He was the captain.
He was my idol.
Then he was from Rome.
The Prince, they called him.
When I was on the field, I changed.
That is, I closed in on myself
and I tried to do things easily.
I succeeded in doing difficult things.
In fact they always put me
to play with the older kids.
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(Totti) Did you see that? Let's rewind.
Pay attention, ok?
I turned my head to look
where my team-mates were.
or where the opponents were..
Another kid won't do this.
He’ll watch the ball instead
When I played, everyone came to watch.
Friends, cousins, uncles.
When you entered the field,
the first thing you did,
was to look for your
mother and father.
If you hear the voices of my parents,
they were much worse than they are now.
Before, they would say:
"Break his legs!” “Get in wrong! "
(WHISTLE)
(Man) Hey referee, when will you give him a yellow card?
- "Mortacci tua!”
- (Man 2) And who doesn't tell him!
(Together) “Mortacci tua!”
(Totti) At that time, I used to go to the curva sud
with my brother, cousins, and friends
with the scooter, every Sunday.
The match started at 3 pm.
We left our house around 9 am.
We would be sitting there and playing cards,
even with people we didn't know,
while waiting for the game to start.
(Together) # E la Lazio merda #
(Totti) When it’s derby day between Roma and Lazio,
there was delirium in the curva.
There was simply 360 degree of hatred.
(Together) # Lazio, Lazio, fuck you #
(WHISTLES)
(EXPLOSION)
(Totti) It's a different game
from all the others.
It was overwhelming.
(Martellini) Be careful,
Sclosa already has a yellow card.
(Totti) There were people
who preferred Roma win the two derbies
than winning the Scudetto.
(PROTESTING VOICES)
(Martellini) Goal!
(Totti) Giannini was the one who gave me
positivity, strength, and competitive spirit.
I saw him as an icon.
When I came back home, I stood in front of  the mirror.
I said to myself: "One day,
I am going to be like him. "
One day, on a Saturday afternoon,
at the end of the first half we were leading 2-0.
I scored two goals with the Primavera.
At a certain point,
they called me off the pitch.
Strange.
I scored two goals, then you sub me off?
Something serious will happen.
(Woman) Hey where are you going? What did he do ?
(Totti) They told me: "Go the the locker room, and take a shower "
"You must leave with the first team for Brescia. "
I was lightning struck.
At first, I didn't even want to leave.
I already had plan for Saturday night.
Disco, dinner with friends.
Everything.
I had become a normal person on Saturday night.
When you get to the end,
it's true, 25 years is a long time.
But looking back at what I have done,
it feels very short.
(Mandolesi) Roma is in the lead
with two goals scored in the first half
by Caniggia and Mihajlović.
(Totti) There were ten minutes left.
I had no hope of playing.
(Mandolesi) Rizzitelli is out, leaving
the place for the young Francesco Totti.
(Totti) Imagining myself on the field,
together with the team, was unthinkable.
It is as if they were making fun of me.
All surreal.
From there, my whole life changed.
From that day on, I started training
almost always with the first team.
Every morning.
Then I went to school.
For me it was a problem.
But it is a train that passes only once.
Fortunately, I managed to get on it.
And to think again, at that moment,
Roma was getting worse and worse.
(Journalist) The longest day
in the history of the A.S. Roma.
(Mannoni) President Ciarrapico
is in jail,
The company is in liquidation.
No prospective buyers to be seen.
(Totti) Fortunately, Franco Sensi arrived.
I have never done interviews.
Leave me alone.
I’m telling you that Roma
will not be without parents.
(Totti) First of all,
Sensi hired a Roman coach
who is also a Roma fan like us.
Mazzone was like a father to me.
He raised me through and through,
both on and off the pitch.
I was lucky to have
him in those years.
(Pizzul) Cappioli, Berretta,
Totti, the boy who impressed the most
among the Primavera ranks.
(Totti) If it was up to him,
he would always play me.
(Pizzul) Again a wonderful control
from Totti,
He's running from the right.
Great play by Totti,
passed to Giannini.
He shoots! Blocked by Pagliuca.
(Totti) To make me grow and show
me that he cared about me,
when reporters kept insisting that Totti must play,
he did the opposite.
(Pizzul) Totti coming off,
very good performance by Francesco Totti.
(Totti) But he never told me
whether he would play me or not.
He announced the formation
two hours before the game started.
It was to protect me.
Then what did he do? In the derby, he threw me in.
It was my first derby.
(Sarta) Winter,
pressed by Carica...
Goal! Lazio!
Signori scored!
Perfect finish by Signori.
Lazio is ahead after six minutes.
Totti entered the field,
not yet 18 years old.
Totti, with the number 16
Mazzone's wild card to level the score.
(WHISTLES)
(Totti) I would have done anything
in that moment.
Before, when a young player entered the pitch
older players would play hard on him,
To scare him.
In that moment,
you have to be a little smarter.
(Sarta), Totti again.
One on one with Negro, Totti!
Totti is inside the penalty box
He fell down. Penalty!
Penalty kick!
(Totti) I felt the slightest contact.
I was thinking: "Now I’ll throw myself on the ground,
hoping that the referee whistles. "
(Sarta) Although I have not seen
any touch on the legs ...
(Totti) I was quite shrewd.
(Sarta) Taking the penalty
is Giuseppe Giannini,
against Luca Marchegiani.
(Totti) Giannini, as the captain,
had double responsibilities
than the other players.
(Sarta) In a very crucial moment.
(Totti) You don't know how hard my heart was beating.
(Seamstress) It's 25 minutes in the second half,
Giannini's running up. He shoots!
Parried away by Marchegiani!
Marchegiani saved
Giannini's penalty kick!
Marchegiani stopped the penalty kick
of the Roma captain
(Totti) The weight of the
whole world fell on me
I could have said: "If only I was the one who took the penalty
surely I would have scored."
But with all those "buts”
and "ifs", talking is easy.
(Sarta) Here comes the final whistle.
Lazio has won the derby!
(Totti) Then, as we lost the derby,
people’s vision became blurred, as they say.
They unleased their frustrations against our bandiera, Giannini.
(Giannini) When they put their hands on
my family members, everything changes.
(Totti) Let’s rewind a little.
I did not remember
that they had shoved him.
It used to be like this.
You see it ? First the fans,
they would all sit up there.
If you lost the derby, then you would have six months
of continuous harassments.
But it was much nicer.
Then it came.
my first goal in Serie A.
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(Totti) For me it was
the realization of everything,
of my entire life up to that point.
Of course, I would have preferred
scoring it under the curva sud.
Then in the end I was there.
A few weeks later, I turned 18.
I’m coming of age.
Guess who showed up at midnight?
The Prince.
Giannini, with a birthday cake.
He gave me a surprise.
He made it the best birthday
I could have ever imagined.
At that time, I had people everywhere.
Down there, in front of the house.
I couldn't go for a coffee.
I couldn’t even play pinball.
I could no longer go out.
I hadn't thought this life would become so hard.
Beautiful, but also difficult at the same time.
I no longer had a private life.
(Mandolesi) Francesco Totti, please give him a round of applause.
Francesco, thank you.
I know you express yourself best on the pitch.
Not in a hot TV studio.
Yes, in fact, on the pitch it is different
than on the television.
Playing for the team of your home city,
the one you supported
when you were a child.
Thinking that two years ago
I was still there in curva sud.
I thank you.
I would also express my gratitude to your mom,
who is a very nice person.
Yes. We'd better leave my mom out of this.
- What's out of this ?
- They all say I’m a mama’s boy
- Is it true?
- True
- It’s a good thing!
- Mums will always be mums.
(Totti) We have a house in Torvaianica,
where all our friends were. All of them.
This was the most beautiful time
in the summer.
The thought of having to leave
with the national team,
the first long trip
I would not exchange it
for everything in the world.
Come on, all together. Cheese!
(Totti) These are all my uncles and aunties.
My father's sister, uncle Augusto.
- (Uncle) Hey nephews, your turn is later.
- # Fratelli d'Italia #
(Totti) Aunt Teresa, aunt Lucia, uncle Ennio.
Mamma mia!
Roberto's girlfriend, my cousin.
Claudia
It was 50 degrees, it was noon.
It was really hot.
Here is my father.
Look at my mother, how young she was.
- (Uncle) Aren't you happy?
- Eh !
(Totti) My brother, who worked in the cinema,
did the filming.
He actually drives trucks.
But to be honest, holding camera on his shoulder
wasn’t necessarily rocket science.
I think this was the first game
I went abroad.
It was a friendly match at Wembley,
the most important stadium that could ever be.
(WHISTLES)
(Totti) I was a simple boy,
shy, and reserved.
It bothered me when they whistled
against me or called my name.
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(Totti) You don't believe in destiny, do you?
I do.
We could only understand destiny
after we have arrived at the end.
Until you have lived it,
don't even think about destiny.
Until something happens to you.
(CROWD NOISE)
(Cerqueti) Here is Roma after Mazzone.
An Argentinian, 47 years old.
In his first interview
as a Giallorossi manager,
He does not forget his Italian grandfather.
"Bianchi” or “Bianci”,
which do you prefer to be called?
I am "Bianchi", because "Bianchi" is from here.
(Totti) Bianchi is the one
who wanted to kick me away from Roma.
Because he,
doesn't like having Roman players in his team.
The moment I knew
that they will not be extending
Giannini's contract,
I sensed that in football
things could change in an instant.
So you might have to roll up your sleeves
and leave without the people you trusted.
Carlos Bianchi
also targetted another player.
He wanted to replace me
with Jari Litmanen.
Litmanen was already Litmanen.
I was a young player.
He was a well-established player.
In February they organized
this tournament at the Olimpico.
A mini tournament among Roma, Borussia, and Ajax.
The tournament was called “Città di Roma”.
For Bianchi it was the right opportunity
to show people how good Litmanen was,
who was playing for Ajax.
I shouldn't have been there
because I had to leave
with Under 21 National Team.
What happened instead? They didn't call me up.
And there I was.
(Piccinini) Eyes on Totti.
Excellent touches, Totti.
Great chance, Totti! Totti ! Totti !
It’s still him!
Totti !
Sublime touch and a fantastic goal!
The fans are all cheered for him.
(Totti) Litmanen had an ordinary tournament.
I played two great matches.
(Piccinini) Totti, with his right foot!
Fantastic goal!
Fantastic goal! It’s him again!
(Bagni) For me, Totti must stay.
He has shown us some great things.
(Totti) The Città di Roma Tournament
was the destiny for everything,
of all my career with Roma.
- The future of Totti?
- Totti's future is with Roma.
He stays at Roma.
- Yes, but maybe a loan move?
- No, he stays at Roma and he plays for Roma.
- Just that.
-  That’s the president.
(Totti) Bianchi said: "Either me or him."
The president chose me.
(Speaker) Zdeněk Zeman !
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(Totti) The first time I saw Zeman,
I was scared.
The rumors that were around said
that he was a maniac.
For him, all you need to do is just run.
Run, run, run until you drop.
Plus he didn't let you eat.
I was anxious.
I was young, I said to myself: "Mamma mia.”
- Look at his pectoral muscles
- (Totti) He went to the gym.
(Totti) Instead I found him
a clean, real person,
nice, easy-going.
Every time I entered the pitch, he said
"With the feet you have,
you always have to shoot. "
"Come in and shoot."
He says: "If you shoot ten times,"
"Ten times it hits the post
and nine times you’ll score. "
Zeman also gave me strength
to improve physically.
He helped me improve my physical stature in every way.
(NOISES OF JUBILATION)
(Totti) During that period, I became the captain.
On one hand I was happy,
because it was my dream.
On the other hand,
I had also seen negative things
associated to being a Roma captain .
For me personally, my responsibilities
have doubled, tripled.
When Zeman left, I thought: "What now?"
That summer I was in Torvaianica.
The news came out
that Roma just  hired Fabio Capello.
Not only me, but all Roma fans and
the players were all happy.
Wherever he went, he won.
Instead, our first year
was quite critical.
We finished sixth,
worse than the previous year.
Then the unthinkable happened.
(Cucchi) Collina has blown the whistle.
The match has ended.
Lazio are the champions of Italy.
(Totti) Lazio winning the Scudetto was terrifying.
All the Lazio fans, with trumpets,
passed in front my house.
I closed everything. Windows, shutters.
For a few days
I did not left the house.
In the end, if they won.
It means that they deserved it.
It couldn't be worse because,
after three days, in the same stadium,
Giannini said goodbye to football.
I was in the middle of the field with him
for the farewell game.
It was supposed to be a celebration day.
Unfortunately it became a nightmare.
In that moment,
people were very angry,
and they vented it all out.
(WHISTLES)
(Totti) For him it was a blow to the heart.
It didn't have to end like this.
It had to end with something better.
Even more beautiful.
But thank you.
(APPLAUSE)
The curtain finally rises
on the new 2000/2001 season.
This is the first time we have
such a strong team.
Certainly, on the three objectives of the season,
we will be able to do very important things.
(CROWD NOISE)
(Totti) And instead,
we started with the Italian Cup
and we were knocked off
in the first round by Atalanta.
There were quite heated protests in Trigoria.
We have to make a huge leap in quality,
also out of respect for the fans.
(Totti) From now on
those who have no character,
those who do not want to play,
they can leave.
(Zampa) Here is the cross.
Goal! Goal! Goal! Goal! Goal!
Goal!
It is Roma's first league goal!
Scored by who else?
The header from our Bimbo de Oro!
(Zampa) Batistuta going wide
in the penalty area. He receives the ball,
He shoots. Hits the crossbar. Goal!
Goal!
Gabriel Omar!
“The Lion King” Batistuta!
(Zampa) Goal!
Goal! Our Golden Boy
(Zampa) Batistuta. He shoots. Goal!
Goal! Goal! Goal!
(Zampa) Here is the cross from Il Pendolino,
for the captain. He shoots. Goal!
Goal, goal, goal!
An extraordinary goal!
An extraordinary goal,
from the left side!
(Totti) I was strong.
(Zampa) Inside the penalty area. Unbelievable!
(Totti) We started our season in the first place
and we stayed first until the end.
We went into pitch on Sunday.
Convinced we’d score at least two or three goals.
(Zampa) Ball for Batistuta. Shoot!
(Totti) There wasn't really another possibility.
(Zampa) Aldair, with the ball
(Totti) You felt that everyone is united.
Compact. Our desire to win.
(Zampa) Free kick, crossbar,
header, goal!
Goal, goal, goal! Vincenzo scored!
(Zampa) Here comes the cross. Goal!
Goal!
We were a winning group.
(Zampa) Just outside the penalty box, he shoots. Goal!
Goal! Vincenzo!
(Totti) It is impossible not to win.
(Zampa) Again, Montella, Montella. The ball is inside the net. Goal!
Goal!
(Totti) The penultimate match
of that season was in Naples.
There were nearly 10,000 Roma fans
Daje, Rome, Daje!
(Totti) If we had won, we would have wrapped the championship.
If Napoli had lost, they would have gone to Serie B.
We brought flags,
t-shirts, as if ...
(Tecca) Totti, Totti ! Goal!
2-1! Totti!
(Totti) And instead ...
(Tecca) Goal! Napoli equalized.
Napoli levelled the scored with Pecchia.
Everyone expected the worst.
(Totti) In the end we were back to
how we started.
With nothing.
(Tecca) 2-2. The Scudetto will be decided on the final match.
Roma needed a win
to make sure they win the Scudetto.
(Totti) Maybe destiny wanted
that the last game
is played at our home.
Rome was totally silent.
It was like someone died.
More than anything, there was fear.
The fear that everyone's dream could just vanish.
Losing the Scudetto with the last match at Olimpico
After 20 years
You would never recover from that.
It would be the end of it all.
VOICES OF PROTESTS
(Repice) Just by a whisker!
Montella!
The ball refused to go inside the net.
Montella had...
It’s still 0-0 between Roma and Parma.
Roma are looking for the goal.
First with Batistuta, then with Montella.
Six minutes and 58 seconds.
Tommasi. Candela shows up
at the opposite side.
Candela now has the ball.
Candela crossing it to the middle.
And it’s goal! Goal!
Goal! Roma 1 - Parma 0
It's the 19th minute of the first half!
Francesco Totti scored Roma first goal!
(Speaker) Francesco!
(Together) Totti!
(FANS SINGING)
(Totti) Scoring that goal was my dream.
It wasn't even easy.
Do you know where other players
would have sent the ball to?
Towards the cameraman.
And after all, I scored it under the curva sud.
It's like I’m sending my love
towards my own people.
Only that it’s blocked by the net
Five minutes before the final whistle,
we won 3-1.
What happened next
was unthinkable.
(Repice) Watch out, it’s the first pitch invasion
The match is suspended, watch out.
Watch out! Watch out! Watch out!
Watch out!
Not this. Not this. Not this.
Not this. Not this.
(Speaker) The match is suspended.
(Repice) The match is suspended. Roma is at risk.
These people absolutely have to get out of the pitch.
You don't have to do that.
You don't have to do this.
You don't have to do this!
(Totti) The kids.
(Repice) You have to get out now!
The game must finish, absolutely.
(Totti) Buffon was left wearing only his underwear.
(Repice) The game must end
regularly, otherwise it's the end.
Antonioli doesn't even have shoes.
We see Capello
in his most bitter expression
in the entire season.
(Totti) If we couldn’t continue while Juve is winning 4-0,
the Scudetto would go to Juve.
The fourth world war would happen.
(Together) Get out! Get out! Get out!
(Repice) The whole stadium screamed:
Get out! Get out of the pitch!
The stadium looks normal again.
The referee has resumed the match.
(Totti) By now we were at the end.
(Repice) The final whistle!
Final whistle!
They are the champions!
The champions! The champions!
The champions in 1942. The champions in 1983.
The champions today. 17 June 2001.
(Totti) I took a risk.
I couldn't take the subway.
Just to return to the locker room,
it took me one good hour.
(CROWD NOISES)
(together) # We are, we are #
#We are the champions of Italia #
#We are, we are #
(Totti) When I scored the first goal, I wanted time to freeze.
In fact, it now stops.
This is for you.
#We are, we are #
(Together) # We are the champions of Italia #
(HORN)
(together) # We are, we are #
# We are the champions of Italia #
(Totti) Look at those people.
Try getting inside the head
of each person on that Sunday.
It is an indescribable thing.
You gave a way to the people
To be happy.
You made the whole city happy.
Doing what? Kicking the ball
and sending it into the net.
(HORN)
(Totti) This is why I have always said
than winning one scudetto with Roma,
it's like winning ten scudetti
with the other Italian teams.
If you go to another part of Italy.
You celebrate it for one day. In the same evening.
In Rome, with the fact that we never win,
that we are passionate,
every day is a party.
It never stops.
The following evening, some more parties.
The day after, some more parties.
Then there was the party at the Circus Maximus.
One million.
One and a half million people.
Sabrina Ferilli had promised,
if we won the Scudetto
she would get undressed and striptease.
In the end she put on a bikini.
There never really was striptease.
I think people at that time,
couldn't care less about
Ferilli's striptease.
With all respect.
(SONG) (CHILDREN, by ROBERT MILES)
(Totti) The summer after the Scudetto
I rented a yacht.
A week with close friends,
In Sardinia.
There was my cousin Angelo,
who was a point of reference for me .
We call him Pisolo
because he falls asleep everywhere.
He is an angel who has fallen to earth.
Giancarlo for us is ‘the Black one’,
because he has the darkest skin of us all.
And he is my right hand.
He is a part of my body.
As soon as we got on the boat,
the first thing Angelo did
was mounting his Roma flag.
Do you see the tattoos?
We made a bet
that if we won the Scudetto,
we would get these tattoos.
Unfortunately, we did.
I am not particularly fond of tattoos.
The following year, at the start of the new championship,
President Sensi gave me the best gift.
As his first transfer,
he bought Antonio Cassano from Bari.
He was a young talent
with a very high potential.
When he arrived in Rome,
I invited him to my house.
And he became like a younger brother to me.
He lived right with us.
We went out, we joked,
we laughed, we had fun.
We spoke the same language with our feet.
We played with our eyes closed.
We entered into a symbiosis phase, on everything.
We became one.
It looked as if the opposition players disappeared.
It is as if they were made of glass.
We just went inside.
Even though we were 50 meters apart,
the first thought was to find Antonio,
or to find Francesco.
Did you know that by
giving the ball to him, or to me,
the ball is guaranteed inside the net.
He is like that. He talks a lot. He is cheerful.
He's an asshole.
He is not ashamed of anything.
Let's tell the truth,
When you stay in one place all the time
It stings you. It kills you.
But having known him then,
he is one of the best guys out there
in the world of football.
We're talking about
when I was 20, 22, 23 years old.
Roma captain. Young,
Single. I had the world in my hand
in that moment.
I used to do fireworks..
I should not think about a girl, shouldn’t I?
And instead..
(together) # I wanna be
the sunshine in your eyes #
# I wanna be the lifelong shooting star #
(Totti) When I saw Ilary on TV, I said:
"That's the woman of my life.
I have to marry that one. "
A friend of mine knew his sister, Silvia.
After two or three months of dating,
we weren't together yet.
And then came that blessed derby.
(Totti) I told her:
"Come and see the game"
She had never seen the derby in the stadium.
She had never even been to the stadium.
(Tecca) The spring derby
between Roma and Lazio
in front of 75,000 spectators
in a scenario of lights. The sounds and colors
are really amazing.
Only the Olimpico.
(Totti) I talked with Giancarlo and Angelo, and I said:
"If she comes,
I have to make a shirt for her."
We started thinking
what to write, what to do.
A drawing, a writing? In the front of the shirt?
At the back? Red? Yellow?
What do we write? "I love you" ?
No, scrap that, we're not even together yet.
Do you see it here?
Under the Roma jersey,
I have a white shirt with a writing.
If I hadn't scored,
no one would have seen it.
(Totti) Totti, beautiful ball.
Again for Vincent Candela,
inside the penalty area, goal!
Goal! Goal! Goal!
What a great goal! What a great goal!
Totti again.
He gets rid of four opponents,
He shoots! Blocked by Peruzzi
Nesta. He shoots, goal!
Goal! Goal! Montella!
Montella!
What a cross from the Roma captain. Goal!
And it's the third goal! And it's the third goal!
Vincenzo again!
Just outside the penalty box. He shoots. Goal!
Goal!
(Totti) 20 minutes before the end
and having made three assists,
I thought: “Looks like it's going to end and
I will not be able to show her my shirt.”
(Zampa) Samuel, Vincent Candela,
excellent tandem with Montella again.
Let’s go, Francesco!
Here is Totti, Totti, Totti. Pallonetto!
Is it going in? Goal!
Goal, Checco. Goal!
Mamma mia!
(Totti) It was one of the best goals
in my career.
Pallonetto.
Under the Roma jersey,
there was the "6 Unica” shirt (Sei Unica - You’re unique)
If I hadn't scored,
maybe I wouldn't even be together with Ilary.
That is destiny.
It’s all written.
I have never followed football,
I don't understand anything.
It is clear that knowing Francesco,
I became interested a little more.
I am pleased to...
A passion for football is growing.
Eh, just a little.
Why is it that we have more and more frequent
of this kind of couples?
Show girls being together with footballers?
(Totti) At that moment, there were
a few pairs of showgirls and footballers.
All gossips.
Together only for two months,
three months, one year,
then they broke up.
90% of the time it was like that.
Instead, thank God
we are still together today.
There is chemistry between us. There is everything.
There is respect.
She helped me grow.
That is for sure.
She is also lucky to have me though.
(INAUDIBLE VOICES)
(Totti) We couldn't do many things
that a 20 year old did.
Or a 25 year old, a 30 year old.
- (Man) You're great!
- (Man 2) You're great, France!
(Totti) Unfortunately you lost some things
Things that when you were growing up,
you wanted to do.
(Together) Ilary! Ilary! Ilary!
(Woman) Francesco! Francesco!
(VOICES)
(Totti) But in the end
love prevailed over everything.
That year was a total disaster.
Roma had four different managers.
Many players were injured.
The results did not come.
There was a risk that Roma
could be relegated to Serie B.
Once I went under the curva
because a captain
should calm down its fans.
Suddenly a water bottle hit me.
I would have hit back and might have killed someone.
The fact that I grew up in the curva,
I tried to suppress those feelings..
The temptation was strong at that time.
Real Madrid wanted me at all costs.
They were offering me 12 billion a year.
When we played against them,
they had Beckham, Raúl, Zidane.
Either jokingly or actually telling the truth,
they said:
“We heard there is a possibility you could play for us.”
"Hurry up, because Real Madrid
is Real Madrid. "
"No other clubs are
stronger than this club."
Of course, I started to have some doubts.
My relationship with Roma was almost over.
People who are close and trustworthy to me,
told me:
"Listen, Roma is Roma, ok, but ..."
"Do you think about it too?"
Everyone would gladly welcome me in Madrid.
Even Ilary also gave her permission.
She said: "This is an opportunity for you
that will hardly happen again."
(Priest) At that time,
some Pharisees approached Jesus,
to test him, and then they asked him:
"It is lawful for a man to divorce
his wife for any reason? "
Jesus said "For this man,
he will leave his father and mother,"
"will join his wife
and the two will be one flesh."
"What God has joined,
don't let man part."
Word of the Lord.
(NOISES OF JUBILATION)
(APPLAUSE)
- Let's go!
- Quick, quick!
Let’s go, brother!
(Together) Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
Kiss! Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
(Totti) Where am I going? How could I leave Roma?
It is unthinkable. It’s impossible.
I'm from Rome and that's it.
Mamma mia. How beautiful Rome is.
I don't know many places in Rome,
because I cannot go out.
Why ? Because I cannot.
I cannot stay undisturbed for long.
It took one minute to look at a monument
And half an hour to sign autographs.
What am I enjoying?
In the end I am a human being.
People don't understand this.
Now they see you
from another point of view.
I am no longer Francesco.
I have also become a monument.
(INAUDIBLE VOICES)
(Totti) I would like to be invisible.
I hope, before I die,
I could spend a day
without being approached for a photo or an autograph.
Without people stopping you,
looking at you and greeting you.
For one day,
I would like to be a normal person.
Will there be such a day before I die?
For me, no.
But in the end
it's like you know everyone.
What I have experienced,
with the people of Rome,
Nobody else in the world has experienced it.
I wanted to marry this project
because it's important.
It is important to both us the players
and for the club and for all the fans.
(Testa) So far Totti,
on the day of the signing
of his virtually lifelong contract
with Roma.
(Totti) Do you know who went to Real Madrid?
Him
Look how he dressed!
Luciano Spalletti
is the new Roma manager.
(Totti) At that moment,
Spalletti was the right coach
to make the leap in quality.
Then, as he always said,
it was a dream for him to train me.
There is some space, Checco! There is some space!
(Totti) I really had
good times with him.
That period was extraordinary for me.
Truly beautiful.
Cristian was born in November.
Holding a baby in your arm. Just the look, the smell...
With Spalletti we had won
nine consecutive matches.
We had to get the tenth,
which in Italy would be the most consecutive wins in
the championship.
Then, in June,
the World Cup began.
Mentally, I was more charged
and more motivated than the usual.
I felt strong.
Everyone wanted to break the record,
especially myself.
Instead, nothing happened.
Destiny destroyed everything.
(WHISTLES)
(Totti) I realized immediately
the extent of the injury.
In the end, when I was holding my ankle,
I took my hand away and everything went down.
When he tackled me from behind,
he broke the nerve.
Ouch!
(Totti) The ankle
turned backwards.
Both the ligaments of my ankle were broken.
Not to mention the fracture of the fibula.
With an injury like this,
80% of the players
would stop playing.
As soon as I was at the hospital, I did MRI scan
I talked to the doctor and he told me:
"We will do the surgery immediately."
"Prof, I will have the surgery if you give me
the chance to go to the World Cup. "
"If not, I won't have surgery."
I was afraid.
I am afraid of everything.
Professor Mariani told me:
"I guarantee,  if you have the surgery immediately,
you’ll have a chance for the World Cup. "
Then he put me asleep and ...
The day after,
without me knowing anything,
- (Journalist) Mister!
- (Totti) Lippi comes to the clinic.
(Journalist) How was Totti's condition?
Very very good,
very peaceful, very calm.
Very positive.
- (Journalist 2) Did he say something
in particular ? - No.
(Totti) He told me:
"I'll be waiting for you until the end."
"Even with one leg,
I want you 100%. "
"You are the one
that will make us win the World Cup."
I see him after the surgery
It made me happy.
It gave me something more.
From there, the struggles for Germany began.
- (Totti) Mario.
- I'll do it.
My grandfather had a wooden leg.
I swear to you, a wooden leg.
- (Man) Did they have it amputated?
- Yes
My mother was there in the evening. Every evening,
He went to his room, took it off
and put his wooden leg behind the door.
I swear to you on my mother, not a joke.
- Now I’m asking, because this ...
- What, am I telling you bullshit?
My grandfather, oh.
Did you know my Grandpa
only had one leg?
- (Man 2) The left or the right leg?
- The left one.
He didn't have his left leg, like me
Daje, Grandpa
(together) # One captain
# There is only one captain.
# One Captain. There is only one captain.
# One Captain #
Push, go, move.
Go, push. One two three four...
(Totti) I passed
three really tough months.
I lost seven, eight kilos,
training every day.
Four hours training in the morning
and four hours in the afternoon is a lot.
I lost my strength. I had lost everything.
But then people transmitted
their strength to me.
People who were looking for everything
to bring home the result,
to get me to the World Cup.
(CROWD NOISES)
(Totti) After a month,
I removed the nail and the brace.
I start walking again.
After two months, I started running.
In a month I had to do everything.
Then the World Championship began.
Spalletti is the one
who was very close to me.
(Scala) Go, bring it to me, Lucia ',
bring it to me, go, son of the wind!
(Totti) After the training was over,
he came to train with me.
He joked. He laughed.
We had a good relationship, at that time.
Then I received the call from mister
Lippi.
He visited me
to really see how I was doing.
He told me: "So?"
"How are you? How are we doing?"
I told him:
"I'm ready.
"I’m at your disposal."
(WHISTLING "IL CANTO DEGLI ITALIANI")
Guido, what are you doing, are you sleeping?
I can't sleep and you sleep?
Guido.
- (Donna, radio) Totti donated
to charity ... - What a drag.
(Caressa) We’re going from the corner.
Pirlo is free. He could shoot.
He is doing it! Andrea!
(Totti) Things were going well for us.
(Caressa) Materazzi jumps. Goal!
(Totti) We qualified from the group stage and we faced Australia in the round of 16.
(Caressa) Here comes Gilardino, Gilardino !
Schwarzer !
- (Totti) It should have been a walk in the park.
- (Caressa) He hit it with his left foot!
- Schwarzer blocked it with his feet!
- (Totti) Instead, it became complicated.
(Caressa) Toni!  On the bottom !
(Totti) Before the match, the manager asked me and said:
"You're not playing today. I’ll let you rest."
I was frustrated.
Then, at some point,
we were playing only with ten players.
I hadn’t thought he would sub me in
with fifteen minutes left.
(Caressa) We still have 15 minutes left.
Totti with a long ball to the left.
Grosso passed the ball.
There is room for a cross.
Trying to attack the space,
Grosso is in the penalty box.
Running inside the penalty box...
Penalty! Penalty kick!
Penalty kick!
Penalty kick! Penalty Kick!
(Totti) There was tension
in that critical moment.
When I was walking, Pirlo turned towards me, saying:
"Daje, score this one, please."
Then some of my team mates went to my right for a drink,
some went to my left ...
They all went away.
Eventually I walked straight ahead
up to the penalty spot.
It was 20 seconds of anguish.
I knew I must not miss this.
We were only playing with 10 players.
If I scored, the game was over.
If I didn’t, we would have gone to extra time, and we’d have been defeated,
because we couldn't take it anymore.
I had everything on my feet.
When I have everything on my feet,
it’s difficult to miss.
(NOISES OF JUBILATION)
(Totti) I was sure that the ball would go in.
(Caressa) It's over!
This is a sign of destiny.
Totti took us to the second round in the first game he didn't play.
(Totti) It looks like bullshit, but in the end, it is real.
(together) Italy!
(WHISTLES)
(CROWD NOISES)
Thanks, Totti!
- Come on Totti! Come on Italy! - Come on Italy!
(Caressa) Totti on the counterattack.
Passing the ball to Gilardino.
Gilardino, to Del Piero, Del Piero, Goal!
- (Caressa) We're going to Berlin. - (Bergomi) Let's go to Berlin!
(Caressa) Let's go to Berlin, Beppe!
(Totti) This is the final against France.
We were on top of the world.
- (Caressa) It's a goal. - (Bergomi) It's a goal.
(Totti) It happens once in a lifetime.
(Caressa) France were ahead.
(Totti) But we were a strong, united group.
We were all opponents, in our respective clubs.
At the same time, these are the same people
who have always played together from Under15 to the national team.
You grew up with them.
Sure, people would tell you about some episodes.
But this is the game of football.
Either you missed...
(WHISTLES)
(Totti) or you didn’t miss.
(CROWD NOISES)
(Totti) It was as if all of Italy
pushed you to raise this trophy.
It is the dream of all kids.
God wanted it to be like this.
I tell you the truth,
there were so many things that I thought then really happened.
(Man) # Happy birthday to you
# Best wishes
# For you
# Happy birthday to Francesco
# Happy Birthday to You #
(Man) We wish Francesco a happy birthday!
(VOICES)
(together) # Happy birthday, Francesco #
(Man) Are we there?
(SONG) "GIOCA JOUER" BY CLAUDIO CECCHETTO)
(Man) Go, talk some bullshit.
Who does not clap his hands, does not walk until tomorrow!
(Totti) Let's say that after 30, time flew.
(Cucchi) Impressive, Roma have crushed Inter.
(Totti) Lots of things have happened.
We have won two Italian Cups and a Super Cup.
(Sparta) Totti strikes, goal!
(Totti) We changed coach. We got up there in the standings.
And then each time, at the decisive moment, we collapsed.
(Longhi) Resounding defeat.
(Totti) Second best forever, as we always said.
Then I won the Golden Boot as European top scorer.
It's not cheap.
My game was always like that.
Entertaining people.
My strengths are:
physical power ...
(Zampa) Totti in the penalty area!
(Totti) My deadly right foot.
Technical skills
And instinct.
(Zampa) Totti's splendid touch.
(Paw) Chest strike, flying dribble, long ball for Batistuta!
(Totti) My weak point?
My touchiness.
When I lose or fail to do something, I lash out too much.
When this happens, it could become nasty.
One thing that I am ashamed of.
But in the end I am a good [person.
I am closed, reserved, shy.
I am a romantic.
But when I was on the pitch, I transformed.
(Pizzul) And he scores! Totti risked to do the impossible!
(Totti) I leave Francesco behind ...
and I become Totti.
Totti has what it takes in there.
I’ll tell you the truth.
Now, look at some of these clips,
You see that when I was 25 or 30 and I was a professional footballer,
I still did the same things I did as a child.
I already had that thing.
Now I realize it,
after a career of 30 years.
Then boom, suddenly ...
France'.
(Totti) I’m 40.
Forty birthdays. Happy Birthday, friend !
You're getting old, huh?
You can play another five years, for what you have shown us.
(Totti) It is normal for the body to change at 40.
But physically I was fine.
(NOISES OF JUBILATION)
(Totti) My physical condition
was due to one person.
You saw him here,
He always stood next to me.
But you didn't realise.
Here he is, Vito Scala.
Here you can see well.
This is him.
That's him, too.
Look, rewind.
Look at Vito's face.
There he is.
He’s here aswell.
Always next to me.
Vito was everything for me.
(Totti) Looks like I don't have the strength,
how is it?
- You have the strenght.
- Do I?
(Totti) He managed me, he gave me advice,
took care of me down to the details,
the particulars.
(Scala) Tonight rich dinner,
protein load,
game and bedtime.
Tomorrow morning, an eggnog.
(Totti) As if he was
an older brother.
(Totti) Take this silhouette back,
here, look.
(Totti) We made the same journey.
We joined Roma at the same time.
When I was 12 years old, he arrived.
We grew together.
He was a physical coach
on the team.
Then he became my personal,
after I became captain.
Vito, always standing next to me,
saw the beautiful and ugly of me.
This is one of the ugliest.
I'm sorry.
You know me, what I’m like
Francesco, at the age of 40 years,
had learned so many things.
As a man, he managed to realize
the dream he had always desired, right?
A family, children,
like a normal person.
Oh!
(Totti) I've had all the people
that have always stood by me.
Friends, cousins.
Ilary.
That for me is the most beautiful victory,
the greatest victory.
We grew up.
The children were raised.
Yay!
(Totti) A lot of things changed,
But the friendships
Always remained the same,
the intact one, the real one,
the one to believe in eternally.
So I was glad I could close
my career with a friend.
(fans) Luciano Spalletti eh eh oh oh
(Totti) He had helped me so much
in difficult times,
after the injury.
I was sure
that it could end in a beautiful way.
I knew him,
He wanted to come back at all costs.
We had a great relationship.
But then, when he came...
Hi.
(Totti) It turned out
the complete opposite.
Something was different
I saw it since day one.
I could see it when he said hello
with “good morning” and “good evening”.
Before, he never said
“good morning” and “good evening” to me.
He would say: [Jokingly] “You asshole, come here.“
He liked me so much that,
He wouldn't even call me by name.
Any coach, the first person
He talks to is the captain.
He asks: “What's the locker room like?
Why didn’t you win?”
In fact, he called everyone else
and and not me.
When I came home, Ilary would say to me,
“Are you sure
that you didn't do anything to him?“
“Maybe you offended him...“
"Me?"
I could see he excluded me.
He didn't consider me.
He let me make one or two appearances
of ten minutes each.
Then against Sassuolo he tells me to warm up
where there were ten minutes left.
To do what?
In that moment the anger, the irritation...
There was a kid looking at me.
He was like Cristian, the same age.
I told him: “Let's do some keepy uppies,
let me see if you're capable.“
“Why was I going to come on anyways,
to take the applause?“
“I don't need applause.“
During training
He only gave a hard time to me.
He came up with reasons
to give me a hard time.
He used to scold me in front of everyone.
Not that he shouldn’t have told me off,
There is way and way.
He was only doing it with me, with others he didn't.
Something was wrong.
Earthquake in Roma after Spallettis decision
to not call up Totti.
(Grimaldi) After the outburst at TG1
of the giallorossi captain,
Spalletti excludes him from the squad
for the game with Palermo.
(Totti) He told me, “It’s not acceptable.“
“You do as you please,
you've always done as you please.“
“You were going to play,
But now I won't play you today.“
“You are not called up.“
“What do you mean I'm not called up?“
“If you want, you can leave.“
I mean, are you kicking me out from Trigoria?
From my home?
(Commentator) Roma fans,
wellcome back to the Stadio Olimpico.
(Totti) A player goes to the stadium
even if he doesn't play.
I didn't really want to go that night.
Then Ilary told me: “No, you will go.“
“In fact, we will all go, if not I'll leave you.“
(Speaker) Coach: Luciano Spalletti!
(WHISTLES)
(CROWD NOISE)
(PROTESTING VOICES)
(Spalletti) I can't accept that one
says these things before a game,
and says these things after a run
of victories as the team has had.
I have to manage a team.
I have to respect all 25,
not just one.
(Totti) There has been
a total estrangement.
For me he didn't exist anymore.
He was the coach, but he no longer existed.
(Man) In this case Totti was wrong,
but I can’t say I'm against Totti
(Man 2) Totti is the symbol of Roma.
(Woman) You can't kick someone like Totti.
(Man 3) You must play whoever is better,
who is more in form.
(Woman 2) As I see it,
neither is wrong or right.
(Totti) I could have very well decided
to retire that year.
But for me it was hard to think that.
I could see that, during practice,
I didn't struggle compared to the others.
Why do I have to quit,
if I'm still okay?
Why do I have to feel bad afterwards and say:
“Fuck, why did I quit?“
He saw it, when I was training,
that compared to the others
I was also a little better.
But he never took you
in consideration,
in fact, he used to make you play two or three minutes
knowing that you couldn't do anything anyway.
(Commentator) There is the goal for Bologna.
Bologna are in the lead.
(Totti) Chance, Gods will,
desperation,
Because that is what matters,
the moment you need a change,
who made that change?
Io.
(Commentator) Ball to Salah, Salah, goal!
1-1!
(Spalletti) I take him in consideration.
I treat him like a real footballer.
I am one of the few
who treats him like a real footballer.
(Commentator) Borriello...
Borriello scores.
3-2 for Atalanta.
Come on guys!
Shot comes in, the ball is still there.
The strike... Mamma mia!
Totti shoots.
Goal ! It’s him!
The captain finds the goal to make it 3-3!
Spalletti wants to immediately put the ball
back in the middle.
(Spalletti) Totti didn't save anything.
The team saved the game.
He scored as he should,
took a shot.
(Totti) He used to let me
play less and less.
Seven minutes? Six minutes.
Six minutes? Five minutes.
(Zancan) He puts it in low, first post,
Martinez lurkes at the back post!
He brings the Toro back ahead,
Roma are frozen, 2-1.
(Totti) In Roma-Torino,
to mess with me
in front of everyone,
He subs me in when it’s 2-1 for Torino,
three minutes from the end.
What do you expect me to do?
(Zancan) Listen to the roar from the Roma
fans for the entrance of Totti.
(Totti) In two or three minutes,
what can one player do?
Can I change a game? No.
Who can do it? None.
How often does that happen?
Once in a hundred million.
(Zancan) Ball flicked on,
far post!
Immediately Totti's goal. Just subbed on!
His first touch, he flies for the draw!
(Totti) Fatality,
after ten seconds I make it 2-2.
(Marchegiani) This
is an amazing story.
(Zancan) He only needed
a second to make an impact.
The ball comes in...
Maybe another handball.
Penalty kick for Roma!
(Totti) After two minutes
he gives the penalty kick.
(Zancan) Two minutes until the end,
Totti vs. Padelli.
(WHISTLE)
(Zancan) Totti! 3-2!
He turned the game around!
Francesco Totti!
Unbelievable.
(INAUDIBLE VOICES)
(Marchegiani) I don't know if this has
ever happened in football history
that a player scored two goals
touching the ball twice.
(Zancan) Cameras picking up
Spalletti.
(Totti) Ilary told me the next day:
“Retire, everything you had to do,
you did.“
But nothing, another year,
another contract,
Because nobody wanted to do it to me.
Do I sign?
(Totti) That extra year,
It got even worse.
From December to March
he never played me.
The first game he made me play
was Roma-Sampdoria,
when there was the great flood.
At the end of the first half he told me:
“Warm up, you’ll enter right away.“
I said: “Sure...“
From there, mentally, I let go.
Here we go.
This is the night
that we never wanted to end.
And you, Roma, what are you doing? Are you sleeping?
(SONG: ANIMA CHRISTI”
OF THE CHOIR OF THE ROMAN DIOCESE)
(Totti) This time has passed.
For you as well, though.
(Ilary) Good morning.
Ao.
What are you doing?
(Ilary) Bye, love.
- (Totti) Hello.
Hi.
How do I do it?
Huh?
- (Totti) What is this, a funeral?
France', score today, huh.
- Come on, captain.
- We're all there for you.
- (Man) We love you.
- (Man 2) Thank you for everything.
Thank you.
- (Totti) Hello.
-You're number one.
- Thank you forever, you are number one,
You are the greatest! Bye.
- (Man) Do you know that lady?
- That's Sabrina.
- She is renowned.
- (Man) Oh yeah?
Yeah!
- (Man) Oh, right.
She was...
in love with Beppe Giannini.
The first fan that was really obsessed.
Oh well.
(De Rossi) The last entrance!
Eh?
The last entrance, the last boot...
(Nainggolan) Francesco, sorry,
they stress you already from 3 o'clock
But you have to tell me things.
(OVERLAPPING VOICES)
(Man) Bend down.
(Man 2) There he is!
(Man 3) He’s not stupid!
(Man 2) Angelo! Angelo! Angelo!
(together) One captain,
there is only one captain
One captain
(Man) Come with us!
(together) One captain
(CROWD OVERJOYED)
(Man) We're all here!
Grandma Marcella is also here!
- Are you ready?
- Where is Chanel?
Are you ready?
I’m not coming.
- Scale!
- Go.
- “Cheese”.
(Totti) They were more emotional than I was.
- Go to the front.
- We’ll fall, Riccardo!
(Totti) This group here,
all the damn Sundays,
Saturdays, Wednesdays we played
they really always followed me.
- Where should I look?
- I don't know.
(Totti) Therefore they too,
at that moment, all retired.
- Take the photo.
- Can you take the photo?
- Break it up.
- Do we have our phone?
(Totti) My father and my mother
didn’t even come to the stadium.
For them it was too hard.
I told them: “You decide,
If you want, I would be happy.“
For me it has always been the same.
Both when I was young and when I’m older,
when you walked into the field
you looked at the stand to see
where your mother and father were.
(Speaker) number 11, Mohammed Salah,
exits the field.
Coming on, the number 10,
Francesco...
(CROWD) Totti!
(CROWD NOISE)
(WHISTLE)
(FINAL WHISTLE)
(CROWD NOISE)
(Totti) So I was there, reflecting.
I was thinking about everything I did,
right things, wrong things.
To myself, I was like,
“It can't be that now I go out
and there's a celebration for me.“
“It is an unthinkable thing.“
(SONG: “SOLO” BY CLAUDIO BAGLIONI)
(INAUDIBLE VOICES)
(CROWD NOISE)
(Totti) Everything I learned,
both in football and in life,
I learned it here,
in the courtyard of my school,
with my friends,
between ice creams.
I might be crazy, but I think
that the harder the challenges are,
More you have to take it easy.
You need to have fun.
Enough about the past, now.
France', you need to know that in front of you
there is a future more beautiful
than you can imagine.
Oh well.
Go back a moment.
(SONG: “GIOCA JOUER”
BY CLAUDIO CECCHETTO)