Carol: If I'm not back in two
weeks, don't keep waiting.
Laurent's missing!
Someone took him.
We'll go through with the test,
but we'll still have
to deal with Daryl
when he comes back.
Isabelle: I promised Lily
to protect Laurent.
We'll go in and get him.
[Screaming]
The Mona Lisa is the most
valuable painting in history.
Insured at a billion pounds
in today's currency.
It was was painted by
Leonardo da Vinci.
Hey, dude!
Woman: Seriously?
- Sorry.
- Why would you do that?
[Indistinct chatter]
♪
S'il vous plaît.
[Cellphone rings]
[Crowd clamoring]
[Cellphones ringing]
[Sirens wailing]
[Alarms ringing]
[Alarm ringing]
[Crowd clammoring]
♪
[Walkers growling]
[Gasps]
No!
♪
[Screams]
[Skin tearing]
♪
[Sobbing]
No!
♪
[Sobbing]
[Sobs]
♪
[Panting]
[Indistinct chatter]
♪
Excuse me?
What do you see
in her expression?
She looks sad.
Perhaps.
A woman gazed on by millions,
never actually seen.
But I see a secret
in that smile.
Something withheld.
You're new.
Just arrived.
From where?
A little east of here.
I came to Paris as a tourist
13 years ago and got stuck.
It's the original,
you know?
From the Louvre.
When it all started,
they protected the art,
not the people.
How are you so sure
it's the real thing?
'Cause I'm the one who took
it off the fucking wall.
[Tray clangs]
Oops.
♪
[Chair thuds]
Bon appétit.
[Indistinct chatter]
Excuse the interruption.
I have no tolerance for bullies.
Marion Genet.
Welcome to the Maison Mere.
♪
[Theme music playing]
[Indistinct shouting,
horse whinnies]
♪
He assigned you to the kitchen,
me to the stables,
which is good because
Julien grew up on a farm.
Maybe they sent him there, too.
Does your Daryl like horses?
The steel kind.
Excuse me.
Never mind.
Highly doubt I'm gonna
find Daryl in a kitchen.
What is all this?
They prepare for an attack
on l'Union de l'Espoir.
Nobody knows for sure
where the Union is hiding out.
♪
Where are they taking them?
The tunnel.
♪
[Gate clangs]
[Gunfire]
♪
What is he giving them?
There have been rumors of
experiments.
Some say that's where
the burners came from.
Mistake that got loose.
[Gunfire]
[Growling]
Genet's trying to make
a stronger breed.
Great. That's just what
the world needs.
[Growling]
[Gunfire]
♪
What if they're bringing Julien
here? Or Daryl?
We'll get to them first.
♪
Sorry.
I'll find them.
I'll come with you.
No, no, it's too risky
with two of us.
Check out the stables.
Look busy.
I'll find you later. Go!
♪
[Footsteps approaching]
[Knock on door]
♪
[Keys jingle, door opens]
[Grunting]
♪
Laurent?
Laurent!
♪
Sylvie!
Laurent!
♪
Sylvie, bear with us.
It's for the best.
Stop saying that.
You're going to kill him.
Come down now.
♪
[Screams]
Sylvie!
[Crowd gasps]
♪
Her faith was weak.
[Water trickling]
[Seabirds crying]
Just a little
farther up.
He's been saying
that for an hour.
Isabelle: He'll find it.
So they think
I'd like Ohio?
Yeah. I mean,
the winters suck.
But summers are nice.
Fishing in the streams,
fireflies all over.
Fireflies?
♪
Found it.
See, I told you.
♪
We can inch up
to the top.
All right.
♪
Ah, it's time.
I'm ready.
Of course you are.
This is heavy.
What exactly do I do
when I'm up there?
Be yourself,
soak in the energy.
Everyone is very excited
about you stepping
into the spiritual role. Merci.
I guess I'm excited, too.
And that's why you are you.
A blessing to all of us.
♪
Hey, when I was your age,
I was a shy kid.
Very nervous.
I wet my pants
during my piano recital.
That won't happen.
♪
I wish Issa and Daryl
were here.
♪
Drink this.
It'll relax you.
Valerian root and honey.
I feel relaxed.
I know you don't need it.
Drink it anyway.
♪
[Choir singing]
My friends, the time has come.
From across France,
from Germany, from Spain,
we've come as pilgrims
to be part of this community
out of a shared belief of faith
in what is yet to come.
[Speaks French]
♪
The journey here
has been long and hard.
Some have had doubts at times.
We've had to be patient to prove
that there is a light
at the end of the tunnel,
a future where we will
no longer be vulnerable
to the bite of
the hungry ones.
♪
Now is the time
to cast doubt aside
and to embrace hope,
to celebrate the inspiring power
of our unity and love.
♪
We are all human,
and even les affamés,
lost to us, carry with them
the memory of love.
So who better to confirm our
faith in Laurent
than someone we've just lost,
but who loved him dearly.
And now
her love will deliver us all.
[Growling]
♪
[Crowd gasping]
[Growling]
♪
[Crowd gasping]
Show's over, motherfucker.
[Shouting in French]
♪
[Gasps]
Oh, good. Come on.
♪
Man: Hey! Hey!
You're gonna have to go out
the same way we came in.
We're not leaving
without you.
I stay and help.
[Man shouting in French]
It's gonna take both of you
to get him down that wall.
Kid, I need you to wake up.
I need your help.
I need to take them
to our secret place.
Okay? The place that we train.
The cave in the woods.
You remember?
Listen to me.
The cave in the woods.
The one
by the big rocks?
Yeah. That one.
Take 'em. You can do this.
Give me a day.
If I don't make it back,
you keep running.
I'll find you.
Okay.
♪
Come on, let's go.
[Men shouting in French]
♪
[Grunting]
[Groans]
♪
[Men shouting in French]
[Man shouts]
♪
[Grunting]
[Gunshot]
♪
[Man shouting in French]
[Groans]
♪
[Grunting]
[Grunts]
♪
[Grunting]
[Men shouting in French]
♪
[Men speaking French]
Hey. I think I was assigned
to help you.
I saw what happened
last night.
That guy with the stew.
The floor. What an asshole.
[Speaking French]
♪
Bonjour.
Stew?
You speak any English?
♪
An American.
I'm looking for
an American.
American?
His name is Dixon.
I'm looking for an American.
Have you seen--
Man: Dixon.
♪
Daryl Dixon.
Who was that?
Do you know him?
I had him,
and I let him go.
This was my price.
Do you know where
he is now?
Why would I tell you?
No.
Because I don't
believe in coincidences.
There's a reason
I found you.
There has to be.
It's a sign.
I don't believe
in signs.
Please.
Darryl Dixon and I...
He's my brother.
♪
He's my only
surviving family.
♪
I'm Carol. I'm Carol.
What's your name?
♪
Codron.
Codron, please help me.
I have come a very long way.
He's the only family
I have left.
He's...
♪
There is an island fortress
on the Normandy coast.
Allez viens!
Hurry up.
If Genet finds him first,
Dixon is a dead man.
[Coughs]
♪
It can only be one place.
Monte Saint Michel.
It is a few hours drive.
♪
Come with me.
I can't.
Not without Julien.
♪
I'm sorry. I got to go.
Good luck, Remy.
♪
Carol.
And you.
♪
[Soft grunting]
[Heavy breathing]
Man: Bonjour.
You're awake.
- [Groans]
- Don't try to move.
You need to rest.
And listen.
♪
This is not
how I wanted it to be.
I was hoping we'd convince you,
that your thinking would evolve,
it'd come around, but...
...no.
Must be hard living
without a semblance of faith.
No organizing principle,
nothing to cling to,
existence spent simply reacting.
A man alone.
It's a sad state.
Fuck off.
Perhaps it's easy
to reject faith
when you live only for yourself.
But I've dedicated my life
to a community of people.
A community that I have
a responsibility to protect.
Faith and hope,
our oxygen and water, elements
crucial to our survival.
And over time,
our reserves, they've run low.
Laurent will replenish them.
The public display of his light
will give our people
the strength
to continue on in the darkness.
Your people don't
even know what you're doing.
I meditated.
♪
I prayed on it.
And I realized
it's our love for Laurent.
That's precisely why he's being
called on to take this leap.
Because only by risking
everything
can we find the true meaning
of faith.
♪
What happens if
you're wrong?
♪
If I'm wrong?
There would be no point
in going on.
♪
So, my friend,
where's the boy?
♪
[Blow lands, grunts]
[Dog barking in distance]
♪
I'm not gonna hurt you.
[Horse whinnies]
Shit.
Easy. Easy.
Shh. Easy.
♪
Go.
[Groans]
Go!
[Horse whinnies]
♪
[Men shouting]
[Men shouting in French]
♪
[Door opens]
Well, hello again.
♪
I'm sorry.
Information is a commodity.
This is the only way I
could think of to save Julien.
I'm sure you would've done
the same for your Daryl, no?
Sabine will take you both
back to Paris.
Drop you wherever you like.
♪
There are two Guerriers
right outside.
You might as well sit down.
♪
It's not bad.
We keep a little vineyard
behind the mill.
What do you want?
I have the same question
for you.
Or I can have you assigned
to the Atelier.
I believe you have witnessed
some of our research tests.
Nasty looking stuff going on
in there.
What's that all about?
Creating a new subtype
of affamé,
more directable warriors.
They will help bring
peace back to the world.
Right.
The war to end all wars.
I've heard that one before.
No more lies.
How did you get here?
I landed two days ago
from America.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
I manipulated an innocent man
into letting me fly
in his plane
under the false pretense
of looking for my daughter.
We had to
stop in Greenland,
where he was almost used
as a sperm donor,
and I was nearly murdered
by insane environmentalists.
[Laughs]
And why do you
want to find Dixon?
I came here to kill him.
♪
Must have done something
terrible to you.
♪
Well...
...we all need
un raison d'etre, don't we?
♪
You can't imagine what
I have done to get this far.
I understand, I do.
Ces douleurs,
these pains we carry,
we women need to learn
to let them go.
Men seem to have
no problem doing that.
They definitely do not.
But we have to forgive
ourselves.
For all the losses.
♪
We can try.
Daryl Dixon has aligned himself
with a group
of religious zealots.
Really?
Daryl is not really
the aligning type.
I believe you've helped us
locate their headquarters.
The island fortress in
Normandy
that my former comrade told
you about.
I'll organize a convoy
in the morning.
You want to kill
Dixon yourself.
♪
I will take you to him.
Get your strength up to go
again tomorrow.
Fuck off.
You'll break soon.
Cowboy.
♪
[Walkers growling]
[Brakes creak]
♪
I used to work here
as a janitor.
♪
At first I was on nights,
almost alone.
I'd sweep the floors
of galleries full
of religious paintings
and wonder why the
greatest artists felt compelled
to depict the same violent
imagery over and over again.
When les affamés came,
we were locked in for a week.
It was there that the paintings
began to make sense to me.
There was one in particular.
Le Deluge.
A desperate family hangs
in peril over a raging flood.
♪
And I realized all
these scenes of apocalypse,
they want to make sense
of the chaos and destruction
that humanity
brings upon itself.
The fantasy
that there's a higher power
that can make things better.
Prayers didn't help us.
Not then and not now.
[Sobbing]
♪
Everyone needs hope.
Yes, but religion is
not about hope.
It's about control.
♪
Keeping the masses in line.
Exactly.
Sometimes it can
turn into that.
Deluded by an opiate
of hope.
L'Union de l'Espoir
thinks we, the masses,
the small and unseen,
are stupid.
That their fairy tales
can control us.
We will show them
they're wrong.
♪
[Walkers growling]
[Rustling]
♪
[Door clangs]
[Gasps]
♪
Look.
[Footsteps departing]
[Door closes]
What happened?
Where's Laurent?
We were separated.
Laurent and Fallou
got away.
I didn't talk.
I didn't say anything.
Me neither.
He'll be alright.
We'll catch up to him.
♪
We should get some sleep.
Get our strength back up so we
can bust out of here tomorrow.
♪
Tell me a story.
Daryl: About what?
I just want to
hear your voice.
♪
There was this guy.
And he left home,
looking for something.
♪
Wasn't even sure
what it was.
And he found himself
far, far away from home.
And he couldn't get back.
♪
That's all he ever
cared about, getting back.
♪
He didn't care about anything
or anyone.
♪
Poor guy.
Then one day,
something changed.
♪
Change is good.
[Speaks indistinctly]
♪
Tell me about
the fireflies.
♪
They're like, uh,
little Tinkerbells
flying around in the sky.
You guys have Tinkerbell here?
♪
Yeah.
[Speaks French]
She saves Peter Pan.
♪
You know I think Laurent's
really gonna like it
when we get back home
to America.
♪
He can go to school.
Be like a normal kid.
♪
And what will I do?
We can do whatever you want.
We can sleep late.
♪
Take long walks, and watch
the sun go down by the river.
♪
That sounds like a dream.
You know, you're right.
I found something here.
♪
[Engines rumbling]
She's got nothing to
say to you.
♪
What are we doing?
Rallying the troops.
Stay close. This is history.
[Man shouting in French]
♪
[Chains rattling]
Where you taking her?
She doesn't know anything!
She knows that we have a mission
here, a greater purpose.
I know where the kid is.
I'll take you to him.
♪
Isabelle has always
had an open mind and heart.
You sadly are beyond hope.
♪
He's in Provence!
I can take you to him!
Isabelle! Isabelle!
♪
You're turning them?
For the greater good.
We've been training
for months. We're ready.
The question is, are you?
I'm giving you what
you asked for.
You're gonna kill
your friend.
Hey! Get off me!
Get off me!
♪
[Marion speaking French]
[Rumbling]
What you're doing
is not strength.
It's desperate
and it's savage.
Sounds like
Daryl talking.
[Man speaks indistinctly]
[Machine-gun fire]
[Walkers growling]
I need you to tell me
where the boy is.
♪
[Explosion]
I don't want to lose him.
♪
[Man speaking French]
[People screaming]
Man: That was good.
Yeah.
Zabel: The number one thing
I was excited about
was the Louvre flashback story
for Genet.
Woman: The Mona Lisa is
the most valuable painting
in history,
insured at £1 billion
in today's currency.
Zabel: When we created
the character of Genet
in the writers' room,
we had this idea
that I always wanted to get to.
There just wasn't room
in season one.
We had
a lot of fish to fry.
But also
it took about a year to plan
and be able to shoot
at the Louvre.
Charrier: You always see
the Louvre full of people,
and we had the Louvre
for ourselves.
That was completely mad.
[Speaking French]
Nicotero: The idea was
having the opportunity
to tell another perspective
of the breakout
of the zombie apocalypse through
the eyes of a character.
Charrier: She doesn't know about
zombie at that time.
They wake up in a nightmare.
They don't know what's going on.
So they kind of see
that people are going mad,
but they don't know
exactly what the danger is.
Nicotero: And I think
what's most important
about this sequence is
it's the genesis of Genet's
transformation into
the character that she is now.
Genet is this simple woman
in love with her husband,
planning to have a family,
and that is taken away
from her.
[Growling]
[Screaming]
Zabel: It's part of the reason
she holds the baby
in season one
the way she holds the baby.
A lot of people
had questions about that.
It's because she's thinking
of the baby
she never had
with her husband.
[Sobbing]
Charrier: The worst in her comes
from that pain that she had,
and I had to build it,
even not knowing exactly
where the traumatize was.
I had to build her
around something
that was really painful
for her.
Zabel: The Mona Lisa
is a figure who--
she's hiding something.
You don't know
exactly what she's thinking,
but she's watching.
And obviously that became
very symbolic
to Genet as a character.
She relates to it.
Charrier: It's one of the
greatest memory of work I have.
Having the Louvre for ourselves
and having that tête-à-tête
with the Mona Lisa,
who can experience that,
you know?
That's a very special memory.
[Sobs]
♪
How are you so sure
it's the real thing?
'Cause I'm the one who took it
off the [beep] wall.
Both Genet and Carol
are characters
who have been underestimated
and misunderstood in the past,
but are very powerful,
each in their own way.
So we thought that was
very fascinating
to put those two characters
together
because of some of
the similarities that they have,
but also the differences.
McBride: Carol absolutely
relates to Genet
in how this world
has affected her.
The losses.
The forgiveness.
The guilt.
The forgiveness again.
Nicotero: It's really
a great opportunity
to see these two women
sort of eye each other up
and figure out
how they can get
what they need
out of each other.
Charrier: Those scenes
in the Maison Mère
I remember really well.
We were
very excited about it.
We were like [Giggling]
you know?
Melissa is very generous.
very calm, and very funny.
And why do you want to
find Dixon?
I came here
to kill him.
♪
Losang: My friends...
...the time has come.
The ceremony is the center,
in my mind, of season two.
It's super important.
And yeah, it goes wrong.
It goes very wrong.
[Indistinct shouting]
What we're shooting today
is a test
of whether Laurent will
survive the bite of a walker.
The ceremony scenes
were wild
because the weather that day
was just like [Blowing]
you know, and you're in
this giant courtyard
of this other castle.
And there was a lot of people
there that day.
Scigliuzzi: Wow, that was a
great day shooting the ceremony.
It was hard 'cause
I had to have my eyes like this.
And the walking was weird
'cause I had to walk
kind of like a walker.
The real twist is
Sylvie's part of the ceremony,
and I gasped [Gasps]
when I read that.
[Man shouting in French]
Aaah!
Sylvie!
[Indistinct conversations]
Zabel: We always wanted
Sylvie to have a heroic story
where she gets killed
trying to save Laurent.
And at the same time,
we were figuring out this story
about the ceremony and the test.
And I said to the room,
"It would be a special walker."
So if Sylvie happens
to have died at the right time,
then she would be the right one
to use as the walker.
[Growling]
[People gasping]
Richman: All the time
we sort of fretted about
telling an actress
that she's going to die.
But the real hardest part
was how, for us,
because her reaction was
she was really excited.
Blanc-Francard:
The fact that Sylvie died
trying to save Laurent,
I think it's the best way
for her to die, honestly.
And I was really excited
to play a zombie.
On "Walking Dead,"
It's the best opportunity
to play a zombie.
♪
They did, like, amazing makeup,
made this prosthetic neck,
as you can see--
goes there-- in silicone,
so to create
like a fake broken neck.
And also synthetic cheekbones
and just sprays me,
like, for two hours.
And after that, you can see
on my hand they did the same.
And they start to draw
on my face
with really,
really thin pencil.
When I saw myself
the first time in the mirror,
honestly,
I was really amazed.
I love the idea
of being transformed
and just be completely different
from myself.
I loved it.
Merci beaucoup
tout le monde.
Scigliuzzi: I guess I'm kind of
sad, not as in my character,
but me, 'cause I'm gonna
miss her if she's not on set.
Blanc-Francard: I learned
a lot in the show.
I'm really grateful
in that I'm full of advices
and great memories that you
can't really forget, I think.
Bye-bye.
♪