I'm going to teach you how to play the accordion.
He likes 70s rock. Neil Young, John Baez, Led Zeppelin.
You're not coming, are you?
Somebody has to stay behind.
It makes sense that it's me.
You want to talk about it?
Why? Why not change your mind?
Every time something good happens,
something bad comes to ruin it.
It's only temporary.
Then why does it feel like forever?
It's a long way to America. You'll be all alone.
I've been alone before.
A lot of times.
I'll make it back.
You can't promise that.
Hey, look at me.
I can't promise that.
I'll see you again.
Go ahead, play something.
It's just my phone.
What do you want?
You want to punish me, I get it.
But you won't be doing any worse than I'm already doing to myself.
Please don't take it out on them.
Here.
Thanks.
See those spasms?
That means he's dehydrated.
Do you know anyone who's dehydrated?
My father was a farmer in Algeria before we emigrated.
Do you know any brothers and sisters?
Two brothers died.
And a sister, Jamila. I lost track of her.
What about you?
I left Cameroon on my own.
When the hungry arrived, I had nothing left to lose.
It's hard to go on when you have nothing left to lose.
Let's check.
They can stay here with the horses.
Shouldn't we all stay together?
It's a bit dangerous in there.
That's exactly what I just said.
Interesting.
Watch out.
The French health system
is the best in the world.
I'm going to check the side.
Yeah.
Slowly.
Do you see the guns?
No.
The plane? Where is it?
What does it matter?
The cause is dead.
No, the cause isn't dead.
Serge Assinta will make sure the prophecy comes true.
They left in the meantime.
We watched them.
No planes in the sky the last two days.
So?
They didn't tell us anything.
Speak.
I think you know.
So what?
Do we have to kill your friend?
The guys.
We have to warn Dixon.
We don't know where they are.
I know.
I don't think he likes me.
Who, Ash?
He's got a lot on his mind.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Because you lied to him.
Something like that.
And now you feel bad too.
People shouldn't lie.
No, they shouldn't.
But I'm glad you did.
If you told Asher the truth, you might not be here.
And neither would Daryl.
You have a really special way of seeing things, don't you?
You're going to make a lot of friends at the Commonwealth.
Do you think Daryl will be able to make it back by himself?
What kind of hose are we looking for?
Something long enough to run from an external tank.
So we don't have to stop.
Yeah, Greenland. I heard about that.
Hey, look man.
I don't really need any help here.
All right, fair enough.
What happened to his parents?
They were wrong.
He's an orphan.
I'm sorry about your kid.
Carol told me.
I was there when she lost Sophia.
I wouldn't wish that on anyone.
You lose a wife or a husband, you're a widower.
A widow.
If you lose a kid, there's no word for that.
I mean, that's too hard of a thing to name.
You got kids?
No.
Well, maybe it's a good thing you don't have that worry.
I worry about plenty.
You know, you came here to save a kid.
You still can.
Wait a minute.
Hey!
I guess I am kind of glad you're coming with us.
I used to live on the street when I first moved here.
Ran away, actually, from our little village to be a singer.
I hated my mother for not believing in me,
but maybe she was just trying to protect me.
She could only see you now.
I wonder if she'd be ashamed.
Where is she, anyway?
Back home, I guess.
In Karelia.
Stop her! Get out!
Stop the car!
What's going on?
You want to get us killed?
Get out.
Perhaps you remember me.
From that cesspool you operate.
Oh, yeah.
You came with a man.
And left alone.
I want the same thing he wanted.
I didn't help him. Why help you?
Ouch.
I know they have an airplane.
Help me find them or your friend's pretty face goes next.
This is why I don't make friends.
And I don't give without getting something good in return.
What about your life?
You could take it.
Or leave it.
What do you want?
To go home.
Back where my people are.
So.
I help you find the boy.
I get the plane.
And the pilot.
So, this way.
We're gonna be able to talk.
This tells us how high we are.
Pretty good with him, huh?
Yeah. Yeah, he is.
Yep.
Brought you something?
No way.
You lug this all the way here?
Well, he allowed one carry-on, so.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Daryl, listen.
Look, I know what you're gonna say.
You ain't staying.
It's the right thing.
For everybody.
It's already settled.
I'm gonna get you home, even if it means me staying behind.
Because if anything happens to you,
I'm not gonna be able to live with myself.
He's right.
Daryl has been here longer.
On the ground.
He knows how to survive.
And you know the plane.
You can help me.
Ash, this isn't about that.
It is about whatever can get that kid back to a safe place.
Looks like you're outnumbered.
Shh.
Easy, Falou!
Jacinta's still alive.
They're coming for Lorne.
You ready to fly?
You gotta go right now.
Come on, help me get this wall down.
Let's go right there.
I gotta test the engine.
The plane is on the other side, near the racetrack.
They won't see you coming this way.
You, you go there.
You and you, there.
I stay here if they're looking for Jacinta.
Go ahead.
It doesn't look like it used to.
Does it?
It will be beautiful again.
Someday.
I hope you get to go home soon.
So, which way?
Through the garage.
It will take you to the track.
Okay.
Go ahead, lead the way.
After you.
You knew.
Jacinta will kill you.
No, God is on our side.
God gave up on us a long time ago.
Do you hear that?
It's the plane.
You two go there, the others come with me.
Carburetor is a little stubborn.
I gotta make some tweaks.
Hop out.
Skip me, is it?
You can turn the fuel on.
That's right.
Just tighten the intake, that ought to do it.
How about it?
Yeah.
We found them!
They found us.
All right, give us some time to get down that runway.
You got it.
Look at me.
I'll see you soon, all right?
I promise.
Get the gun.
Oh no.
Go.
No, go!
Help me move this!
Are we good?
Yeah.
Yeah, we're good.
Shit.
Come on, come on, come on.
Suck it, motherfucker!
I had it.
Yeah, I know.
They say they'll be here by sundown.
We can head out in the morning.
Who are these people?
A couple I met at the demi-monde.
They can help us get to England.
From there, you may find a way across to America.
They speak English?
They're from Scotland, so...
No.
It's overheating.
Like a stove.
If only we had air conditioners.
It's better in England.
No, no.
I went to London when I was a kid.
The food is awful.
Confirmed.
You can come, you know.
I don't know.
I like Paris.
There's something special going on here.
And I hope to find Jamy again.
Good luck.
Hey, pal.
Maybe your pals could stop pointing those things at us.
Oh!
This is Fiona and Angus.
They will be our guides to the islands.
This is...
Daryl, Codron, Carol and Akira.
Hiya.
Nice to meet yous.
Some supplies to get through the checkpoint.
Supplies.
Wine.
A bit of food.
Very good.
Aye, that should be plenty.
At least one more than we need.
Oh.
We were in Edinburgh for a few years.
And Fiona said,
to hell with it.
Let's get hitched.
I thought that Paris would be romantic, you know.
We were young.
Young and dumb.
You know, I always had this dream about France.
The history, the culture, the food, you know.
What was it really like?
Before the world turned to shite.
My France.
Perfect.
Well, most of the time.
Of course, some things were not always so good.
I had these neighbours,
Desjardins, the White family.
They were not so nice.
My food smelled bad.
I played music too loud.
I worked in a hospital back then.
So, I came and went at all hours.
They complained about it.
And Monsieur Desjardins,
he lost his job.
Drank a lot.
Started calling me names.
Terrible words.
Tell me I should go and live in that good door.
With my people.
Then, boom.
The world changed.
We stayed in our flat.
Hoping to hold out.
Wait for this terrible thing to pass.
One night, I hear a knock at my door.
I grab my weapon and look out.
It's him.
Holding his two-year-old child.
Limp in his arms.
Pleading his eyes for me to help.
He thinks she's dead, but no.
Her airway was blocked.
And she passed out.
I got her breathing again.
She smiled at me.
And the father?
I took her and left.
But I saw gratitude in his eyes.
So,
the apocalypse put an end to racism?
Well, maybe it leveled the field.
A tiny bit.
Only two kinds of people now.
The dead
and the living.
We need more wood.
Wait, I'll come with you.
Okay.
Night-night.
Night.
Your story saddened me.
When the girl survived.
What happened next?
Well,
the family moved out.
And
I used the furniture to make wood.
It kept me warm all winter.
Goodbye then.
Tomorrow I'll be too shy.
Come back with us.
Forget Jamila.
Let's say goodbye again.
I'm sorry about what happened
to the nun.
She's probably in a better place now.
Like my brother.
His name was Michel.
It's a
very old name
in France.
I used to
laugh about that with him.
He hated that.
It was so hard to see him that way.
Having to
finish him off.
In a way, you
you put an end to a part of yourself.
Yeah, I can imagine.
You never told me what happened
when you killed Michel.
I didn't kill him.
That girl beat me to it.
What?
What girl?
A skinny girl on the road.
She was with some old guy who
tricked me into thinking he was blind.
She told me it was you.
What did you expect her to tell you?
So what?
Everything starting down in Marseille.
The abbey.
The mother's house.
The nun.
The things I did.
All of that just because of her.
I guess she was a pretty good liar.
You alright?
They should be there by now.
Ezekiel's probably showing Ash around.
Maybe Judith is trying to teach Florent
how to use her katana.
It wasn't easy there.
Never felt like home.
It'll be different this time.
We'll stay together.
I can't remember her face.
All I see
is of her after at the farm.
It was her before.
That little girl that I would read stories to.
Sing with and laugh with.
Time took that Sophia away.
All that's left is what came out of the barn.
It's more than that.
It just seems that way.
I'm tired, you know.
It's been so long,
it all just got churned up again.
Her.
Lizzie.
Henry.
Hey.
None of that's your fault.
Come here.
We keep going.
Alright?
That's what we do.
So that's it, huh?
A bit worse for wear,
but we can still get through.
Wow.
The tunnel.
50 kilometers downwind.
Took us about nine hours to walk this on the way here.
Take care.
You too.
We'll all be here thinking of you guys.
Let's go.
I know you regret where you are going.
You're not coming?
I have a reason to stay now.
I didn't warn you.
It's been a privilege fighting with you guys.
Thank you for everything.
Brothers in arms forever.
What did he say?
He said you're brothers in arms.
That's what I thought he said.
Your French is getting better.
So what's England like?
England's shite.
Not bad, huh?
Actually, army took over and got things locked down pretty quick.
The island was good when we left.
Aye, but they're still English, so they're shite.
Now Scotland, there's a wet fucking dream.
What the hell is that?
Guano.
Guano?
That shit.
Don't touch it.
Don't worry.
It's...
That stuff's psychoactive.
You're under the channel now.
Well, it does feel in holes.
Drowning's not anything I had on my to-do list.
Don't worry.
Pressure will crush you to death before you get your hair wet.
That's comforting, thank you.
How do we know how far we've gone?
That yellow door leads to a service tunnel.
There's one every half kilometre.
Only 91 to go.
Now hold up.
That must be a checkpoint.
English? Why so close to France?
To keep out the fucking French.
Hey, relax, mate.
Just keep your guns away.
Let me do the talking.
You'll just piss them off.
Hello?
We're British.
Please don't shoot.
We come bearing gifts.
Angus, get it.
Vino!
We've got Vino!
God save the Queen!
I guess they're not gonna be needing a wine.
Not for us.
And God said,
let there be...
They killed each other.
Why would they do that?
Maybe it's the guano.
If you breathe it in too long, you can start to see things.
Start getting you paranoid.
They'll lose their minds.
Let's keep moving.
What is this?
Bioluminescence.
Some animals and plants generate their own light.
Like fireflies.
Yeah.
Exactly.
Walker.
All right, follow me.
Single file.
Keep quiet.
You OK?
Don't worry about me, Froggy.
It's OK.
You all right?
Where's Carol?
You killed my brother!
Stop!
It's me.
Fiché!
Hey, mate.
Here, put it on.
There you are.
Sorry, pal.
There's not enough masks for the lot of us.
We've got people waiting for us back home, mate.
You can't just leave them here.
This has been so long.
I could come with you.
Where's my pistol?
Where's my pistol and my bag?
Where's your bag?
I'll give it to her, eh?
You think you've had enough?
That there's nothing left inside you?
You think it's over?
But you won't die here.
Not like him.
Remember when we first met?
What I told you.
Good luck, Mr. Dixon.
TO BE CONTINUED...