Episode 1
Come on, let's go.
Not in the head.
Come on, come on.
This one.
The guy on the left.
Him, him, him.
Look.
Come on, shoot him.
Come on, let's go.
Yeah, yeah, okay.
He's still alive.
Look at the girl over there.
Yeah, she's moving.
He's moving.
They're all dead.
Ah.
No!
Stop it!
Shoot him!
Get us out of here.
Hurry up!
Go, go!
What are you doing?
Why are you stopping?
They're coming!
Over there ! Over there !
Shoot the mortar !
RUN !
Hold still !
Go on ! Up the mountain !
What about you ?
Tell Dixon I did it for the boy.
Come on ! Come on !
Come on ! I'm here !
I'm sorry we're getting there.
But you have to tell us where he is.
You made the choice.
When we first met,
Laurent was six.
I'd heard of him.
A child torn from the womb of an affamé.
From a horrific ending,
a miraculous beginning.
We met with the boy, we evaluated his gifts, we...
found him to be special.
As Père-Jean had said he would be,
as you said he would be.
For years, the good father and I stayed in touch as best we could,
and then when it seemed time, we summoned the boy here.
Time for you or time for him ?
Time for us all.
To be free again.
There was only one reason.
You feared losing control.
I can see that now.
I'm sorry your will is weakened.
I want to fortify you,
and everyone who's feeling tired and hopeless.
What you're doing is not strength,
Lausanne.
It's desperate, misguided, and it's savage.
It sounds like Daryl talking.
No, that's me.
The part of me that was asleep until I met him.
The part that doesn't believe in false prophets anymore.
You yourself said how special the boy was all those years ago.
He is special, he thinks and feels in a way that humanity needs
in order to survive.
But he's human.
He can bleed, he can be hurt.
He can die.
Like Jesus, like Mohammed, like Buddha.
This is a waste of time.
Stop it !
Sister,
we're going to offer the flock proof of their faith.
It must be done.
Do you understand ?
And so I need you to tell me where the boy is.
They're at the gate. They're on the way up.
The army of Jeunet is in the village.
Well, they're coming.
Lausanne !
We must go !
The soldiers are coming !
Come on !
Excuse !
Don't move !
Get back on the other side !
Cover me, let's go !
Are you all right ?
Were you stabbed ?
Sit down.
Just breathe.
Careful.
Have a look.
Looks pretty clean, that's good.
My name is Carol.
Easy now.
Keep that pressed pretty tight, okay ?
Can you do that for me ?
You're shivering.
What are you doing here ?
I'm looking for a friend of mine.
From America.
Come on !
She's right there.
No, no, no !
It's okay.
Shit !
Here.
Hold this real tight.
We're getting out of here, come on !
No !
It's too late.
It's not too late.
Not like this.
Just make sure he's okay.
We can do that together.
Make sure he's taken care of.
That he knows I'm always with him.
Okay ?
Okay.
I can see them.
The fireflies.
They're so beautiful.
Come on, move faster.
Where are we going ?
Let's go.
Hey.
You know, I got somebody ready to take us home.
The pilot of the plane back in Paris.
Everybody misses you.
Connie, Judith, they'll all be so happy to have you come back.
Are you hearing me ?
You knew her before, didn't you ?
She's doing pretty well, I know.
Who is she talking about taking care of ?
This way.
It's over.
Give up.
The night is ours.
What ?
They're gone.
Who's gone ?
Look, Daryl, maybe we should just head back.
No.
Not without the kid.
Is that...
Is that who Isabelle was talking about ?
He was supposed to meet us here.
It's cold.
Fuck !
Hey.
He was here.
Okay.
He left us for me.
Okay, okay, hey.
Let's find him together, okay ?
Okay.
Come on.
We must have just gone through here.
We can't be too far behind.
So, Isabelle...
Yeah, we helped each other out.
I don't think I'd be here without her.
You're a pilot.
What did you do ?
Just load up the plane and fly all the way to Maine ?
I stopped in Greenland to refuel.
That's a whole other story.
You just left on a hunch ?
Left everybody back home ?
Yeah.
Just flew halfway around the world on a feeling.
We were supposed to come back.
Yeah, I was trying.
Well...
One thing's for sure.
Not in Ohio anymore.
Depeison.
What ?
It's a French word.
Uh-huh.
It means a place that makes you see things different.
Oh.
What ?
Is she speaking French ?
Me, you, here ?
This is crazy.
No, it's stupid.
It's crazy.
I met a guy who helped me out.
His name is Codron.
He said he knows you.
I met him at that Maison Mare place.
Well, Janae got him.
She's a piece of work.
He helped you find me ?
He said he did it for the boy.
Oh.
Where's the boy ?
Is he with the American ?
You won the battle and left the boy alone.
But I intend to win the war.
The war ?
Our war should be with the dead.
With hopelessness, with despair, not some innocent child.
Empathy, concern.
I can see how you love this ship and this mission.
Do you think all this time I've been relying on only the truth ?
We found the nun.
Isabelle.
She won't tell you anything.
Not anymore, no.
Was she hiding the boy ?
Did she fear what you would do to him ?
She had nothing to fear.
But you do.
I fear for my people.
For the future.
When the boy escaped,
I feared that God was protecting him from me.
I doubted myself, even my faith.
But I don't anymore.
Because I realize now that God was protecting him from you.
Does the American work for God ?
We all serve him.
Whether we believe or not, even you.
So if I find the boy,
it will prove God is on my side.
I wouldn't worry so much about the future.
You don't have one.
What ?
High school French.
Which means...
Where's the train station ?
If you find a train, you do all the talking.
Madame Bourgeois.
If you'd miss a verb, she'd crack your knuckles with her ruler.
She was a math teacher too.
Wasn't very good at that either.
You know, I never really went anywhere before.
We've been places.
You know what I mean.
When I was a kid, my dad had this whole globe next to the TV.
And he'd spin it around.
Think how easy it would be to see the world.
So why didn't you ?
I became a mom.
It was my world.
You said on the radio that time someone came back.
Who was it ?
It wasn't a person.
It was a feeling.
Everything at Commonwealth just got so quiet.
All that old stuff came back like ghosts.
So I got out of there.
And I was worried about you.
Trash ?
Yeah.
More than two people.
Someone caught up to him.
Mr. Dickson ?
Who the fuck are you ?
Saint-Isabelle ?
Welcome.
I'm Didi.
He's Théo.
The boys said you would come.
I'm out for a drink when I see them.
Didi, she loves the white mushrooms.
Thank you.
It's good.
No, morning's fine.
It's pitch black out there right now.
What ?
Enjoy dinner.
Rest.
Sister Isabelle knows best.
When was the last time any of this worked ?
Oh, who can remember ?
I learned to drive in this truck.
And learned a few other things too.
But you grew up here ?
Fourth generation.
We sold carrots to the Germans in the first world war.
Nazis in the second.
And American soldiers after that.
Armies come and go.
We're still here.
This one's shot.
It's been converted though.
You got any ethanol ?
In the barn.
This one ain't bad.
Let me find a battery.
One that holds a charge.
A few hoses ?
Oh, I know a place to find these things.
Let me get my walking shoes.
I can take you.
Alright.
I miss young people.
All the children grew up and left so long ago.
It was nice having Laurent here.
He's only a day.
Like you said, he's a really sweet kid.
He's very fond of his aunt Isabelle.
And Daryl, he went on and on.
Daryl's a really good influence.
And we talk about the two of you.
Sometimes, children see things we're afraid to look at.
Why do I get the feeling you're trying to tell me something ?
Laurent thinks that Daryl loves you but won't say it
because if he says it, he won't be able to leave.
It's a little more complicated than that.
Not to a child.
And not to me.
I know how rare love is.
How long have the two of you been married ?
Daryl ?
We're not married.
My husband died years ago.
My children, grandchildren, everyone's gone.
You seem so happy.
For a long time, I wasn't.
Like Daryl.
I was turned between the world I lost and the one I found.
But...
one must look for a way to...
keep living.
Not so easy sometimes.
Reasons are everywhere.
Good song.
Love.
Here you go, darling.
Thank you.
I'm glad he put on his walking boots.
This place gives me the creeps.
The walkers have walkers.
Hey !
Bonjour, madame Dicasse !
Kind lady.
And good dentist.
I still have lots of teeth left.
Hey !
Monsieur Roux !
The baker.
Very quiet.
Makes more noise now than when he was alive.
Sadly, this whole street has passed on.
Couldn't you just bury him ?
There's only old people left in the village.
Old people burying old people ?
Too hard.
So when someone dies,
we lock the gate
and pay respect when we pass by.
That's a new one.
Yeah.
Monsieur Toussaint !
Stop !
You stay here.
I talk to him first.
All right.
Didi says Laurent idolizes you.
She just spent one day with him.
He made a big impression.
Sounds like he's gonna do really well at Commonwealth.
He's got friends in Paris.
It's better he stays with them.
Better for who ?
He's your responsibility.
Maybe I don't want that.
What about the kids back home ?
This is different.
Is it ?
Yeah.
Yeah, it is.
I don't want to lose him.
Will you end up like me ?
Is that what you're afraid of ?
No.
No, I ain't afraid of that.
Yeah.
Come on.
Hurry up.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, this will work.
American ?
Yes.
I like the United States.
Thank you.
I'll help you.
What is it, dear ?
You can tell me.
I had a little girl.
I got through it.
You will too.
Go ahead.
We'll go in together.
Go ahead, give it some gas.
Just a little.
Stop !
I said a little.
There was a little.
No, that was too much.
How am I supposed to know how much is too much ?
Well, you listen.
And if it sounds like it's too much,
then it's too much.
Maybe you're too much.
What ?
Please, don't stop.
It's a good show.
Like an old married couple.
I'm glad you're enjoying it.
Mr. Pouvoir, you hide here.
They're going to kill him.
We don't know that.
Get down.
I guess Janae won the battle.
I know you had people there.
Isabelle and Laurent.
It's from Judith.
How is she ?
She didn't want me to go.
Part of her knew I had to
if there was a chance I could find you.
I guess I'm just surprised
you got so close to people here.
I didn't mean to.
It's hard to explain, I guess.
Well, if you ever want to try.
Hey.
I'm glad you came.
Me too.
You leave ?
Long trip.
Oh, too bad.
Did he make something special ?
Her truffle eggs.
They're very truffle ?
No, huh ?
Like sex.
Or the tongue.
Forgive me, sister.
Hey, Vinnie.
I don't see.
We'll make it quick.
Come on.
Jesus.
I'm sorry.
These are the best eggs I've ever had.
Yeah, truffle.
You might have to give me some of these.
You need a good eye
and a lot of patience.
They're very hard to find.
Only for special occasions.
Thank you for the car.
And for all you've done.
What are your plans ?
After you find Laurent,
will you stay in Paris ?
How long we're still working it out ?
What are you doing ?
Where are you ?
What does it mean ?
Who they are for you ?
Theo, why ?
For you, my love.
For us.
Do you know who those people are ?
Armies come and go.
You don't survive by picking the losing side.
Come with me.
Crazy old man.
What a woman.
Sex.
Sorry.
You can hide down there.
Sir ?
Do you know why I'm here ?
Yes, madam.
They left just after breakfast.
We did what we could
to reassure them,
but they were wary.
Theo.
I'm going to search the barn.
Cover me.
I'll get the car.
It smells good.
May I ?
You'll be honored.
Truffle.
What a refinement.
We don't have salt,
but we have truffle.
Who are we looking for ?
They are very dangerous.
It's the enemy,
in truth.
We are at war.
Do you know who I am ?
Yes, I heard about you.
By my father.
Admirable longevity.
No.
He died young,
of wounds received
while fighting the Maquis.
But he told me about people like you
who came to the village
during this other war.
He was also looking for children
to put in trains.
Is that how you see us ?
Guigui.
I told you,
they left hours ago.
How can his eyes
still be warm ?
They are here somewhere.
We'll search the house.
No.
Let them do it.
If there is one thing
that the dead are capable of,
it is to scare the living.
Come on, let's go !
All right.
What is it ?
Quick, quick, quick !
Yes, come on, quick !
Be careful.
They are coming !
About how someone like you
could turn...
turn into this.
Do you know what else I've seen ?
The City of Lights,
gone dark,
where the wealthy
fled to their villas
and their chateaux.
Families huddled in terror
under the Pont Neuf,
as badgers took the powerful
down the Seine for refuge.
So you're making up for that now ?
And while the great works
were safe,
I saw my love
devoured by the monsters they made,
five feet from me,
on the other side of the glass.
Have you ever known
that kind of loss ?
I'm sorry.
We're all together, you know ?
Yeah, I do.
And I never ever
stopped trying to get home to you.
The longer I stayed here,
the harder it got.
You loved her.
You know Laurent's coming home with us,
right ?
Yeah, I know.
Madame Jeunet is dead.
Killed by the American.
She went after the boy
and now she's gone.
There isn't proof
that God is on her side.
Marine's way was not enough.
But neither is yours.
So now what ?
All is forgiven,
my friends.
All is forgiven.
Power of the living,
welcome to the union of hope.
Let us unite our dreams
for a better, stronger future.
Let us merge our dreams
Ahead is the promised land.
Laurent will take us there.
Let's find the child.