I'm going to show you how to use it.
How's it going, Bastien?
It's not easy.
We're all trying to figure out what happened at the nest.
Balozard was a good guy.
He brought along good people like Emile.
But we stayed the same.
We move forward as best we can.
What about Laurent?
Laurent has always been a symbol of what the future can offer.
For me, he's still there.
Here, with us, he's safe.
We were expecting someone?
No, no, there's no one.
Everyone in position.
Open the door.
You?
How did you get here?
Please, let me explain.
What do you mean you're not here to kill Daryl or the world?
He saved my life.
All of us.
Daryl, Isabelle, Sylvie.
On a road over there.
They were going to kill us, but he stopped them.
He let us go.
I have information on Juni.
And Yoracho.
We know I was there.
Your boss was caught by Jeunet.
They locked him up.
They did?
Good.
That's what he deserves.
What about Isa?
And Daryl?
Did they make it out alive?
I don't know.
There was a woman.
What woman?
An American. She was looking for him.
We were separated after the fights.
Is her name Carole?
You're right.
Bringing the kid back, that wasn't part of the plan.
Is he going to be alright with that?
Sure, once I explain things to him.
You know it's probably better if I talk to Ash alone.
He's not going to be that comfortable with you at first.
He knows you were looking for me though, right?
It's just that he's lived alone all this time.
It's the first time out in the world.
He's nervous.
I don't want him to overreact.
Look around. This place ain't safe.
Not really. You know I got it.
You don't need to take any dumb risks.
How do you think I found you?
No, I'm coming.
Okay, look. Look.
When I said to him,
to persuade him to do this whole thing,
I embellished some facts a little.
So you lied?
You could say.
You going to tell him I'm your brother or something?
No, nothing like that.
Nah, I'm coming.
I'm going to do all the talking.
Please let me get in front.
Jesus.
Looks like Ash has been busy.
Ash?
It's Carol.
Wait, wait.
Ash!
Are you here?
Hi.
Over here.
Is that guy still alive?
Where's Ash?
The man that was here, where is he?
The man? What happened to the man?
He never came back.
What were you doing here?
We came to find the plane.
It was us, really.
Not you.
What are you saying?
Please.
You'll kill me.
You'll kill me, please.
I got this.
You think these folks are going to be able to help us find Ash?
Yeah, I hope so.
He's not like us.
He's nice, he's gentle.
Do you have a crush on him?
No, I like him though.
He's a really good person, not easy to find these days.
Who's that lie you told him? What was that about?
I told him I was looking for my daughter.
Sophia?
I don't even know where it came from.
I was just searching for a reason, thinking about you.
Everything we've been through, all the loss, and I just...
Maybe I do know where it came from.
Hello.
Hi, Nadine.
Cyril.
You made it.
Yeah.
What made you come here?
I didn't know where to go.
You were with the ladies.
Locking you up in the mother's house made me think.
Thinking about my brother, Michel.
My parents.
The men in the south.
All dead.
All those I wanted to protect, all those I loved, they're gone.
And why?
Because of me.
There he is.
You're back.
You okay?
Yeah.
And Carol, from the Commonwealth, right?
That's right.
Bienvenue, mon ami.
I prayed for you.
And Judith, and RJ, and Ezekiel.
I've heard a lot about you.
Where's Iza?
Hey, I'll talk to you for a second.
We heard Jenna was dead.
But we were unsure it was true.
It's true.
Maybe now, it will be safer here.
I hope so.
For all of you.
How about this friend you're looking for?
What do you know?
He must be in trouble.
She's with my mother now.
Yeah.
She died protecting her.
That's what she wanted.
Like Sylvie.
And the sisters.
That's right.
It's a terrible thing to think of.
A world without them in it.
Yeah.
Yeah, it is.
She loved you.
She told me.
You know, Isabelle and I were talking
about the three of us going back to America.
We could still do that.
Together.
Carol has a friend who has a plane.
We just gotta find him and then we'll do that.
Alright?
Do you think that someday,
this will all be over?
And we'll be able to do normal things?
We'll be able to go to school with other kids?
See a movie?
Ride a bike?
Then we have something like that back home.
Hell, I'll teach you how to ride a bike.
I don't think so.
I should stay here.
And you should go back where you belong.
That's what you always wanted.
I was wrong.
It's not what I want.
Hell, it's not what you want either.
It's different now.
Why?
Why is it different?
Because I feel at peace here.
Don't be sad.
I'm happy here.
And you'll be happy too when you go back home.
You sure?
Good night.
Honey, can you sit here?
Yes, Jessica?
Where are we going?
To look for Ash.
Why?
You wanna talk about it?
No.
You mind if I do?
I know you really wanted him to come.
And I know he's not.
And that sucks.
And I'm really sorry.
I let him down.
Can't really blame him.
So what, he's getting back at you?
I probably deserve it.
I mean, I'm here, she's not.
Right?
And now you're replaying every decision.
Thinking of everything you could have done differently.
It's a pretty long list.
Yeah, me both.
The past has just become
one big giant hole of what ifs.
Why us?
You and me.
Why do we get to go so far?
Luck?
Bad luck, maybe.
I just kinda wanted to tell the difference.
Carole.
Hey.
It won't be easy tracking down your friend.
The stranger out there alone for that long.
What are the chances you'll find him alive?
I found him alive.
What are the chances of that?
Come on, Wayne. You know where to look.
There's still only one place to go for information.
Hell yeah, I'm not too popular there.
What place is that?
Welcome to the Demi Mall.
Bonjour, mon beau.
Bienvenue.
Bonjour.
Tu veux que je te fasse kiffer?
No, I'm good.
Thank you.
Et toi?
Mm-hmm.
Beso.
Yeah.
What?
Nice man.
I guess not anymore.
What's that right there?
Daryl Jackson.
I heard you were a dad.
Not yet.
Make yourself at home.
All right.
Hey.
I love what you've done with the place.
Listen up the rules.
Rules are so British and people want to be free, especially French people.
Queen never understood that.
I mean, some of his men did.
Others needed a little convincing.
Hey, good job.
You're very popular with the guerrilla.
When the queen dies, the bees scatter with the honey.
And who are you exactly?
She's a friend of mine.
Oh, another friend.
What happened to the last one, the nun?
She died.
And the boy?
Somewhere safe.
No one can find him or hurt him.
I did what I had to.
It was Queen.
I'm sorry for Aeneas.
What do you call it?
Collateral damage.
Well, you can make it up to us.
We're looking for someone.
Another American?
Oh, people are everywhere.
How exactly did you come to France?
Does it matter?
Not to me.
But you show up around the same time an airplane landed west of the city.
Be careful.
Some people will do anything for a way out.
Yeah, we'll keep that in mind.
In fact, I hired a few men to track it down.
They never came back.
What about our friend?
I'll put out a word.
What is it?
This red one, where did it come from?
Julia?
Is that two of them?
Two warriors brought them here four or five days ago.
From the mother's house.
Mother's house?
That's what it used to be.
Nothing left.
From what I hear.
We'll need a car.
And weapons.
Well...
First of all...
What does it taste like?
Sweet.
Well, I think.
It's been so long, I don't even remember.
Why did you want to kill Daryl?
Because he killed my brother.
I was angry.
Because you love your brother too much?
Anger is...
It's a disease.
It can make you do terrible things.
Was your brother a bad person?
No.
He was afraid.
Fear can also make us do terrible things.
I should have protected him from all that.
You know...
What you told me on the road...
I believed you.
God loves us all.
And for the first time, you see, I had...
I felt like he was looking at me.
To see what I was going to do.
What decision I was going to make.
And you did what you had to.
But I hurt you a lot.
I'm sorry.
I've already forgiven you.
And I hope that one day,
you'll forgive him too.
Put your guns down.
We don't want any harm.
Don't worry.
No guards.
Yeah, I noticed.
You okay?
Just thrilled to be back.
Yeah.
Yeah, good times.
Don't be alarmed by the Gurriers.
They're brothers and sisters,
united in our cause.
But the message will be lost
without the boy.
Laurent is the chosen one.
He needs to be protected.
We're hoping he's here.
We sent Laurent to you,
at the nest.
He was taken from us,
lured away by the Americans.
Then, must I find him?
Make preparations.
We go out at once.
We split into groups to cover more of the city.
Come on, let's go.
Wait!
Go on.
On the table.
Over there.
Find him.
Matisse, come with me. You go there.
You two, go there. You too.
I'll check in here.
Go.
I'm looking for some kind of trouble.
If I don't make it back,
I want him to know I tried.
Hell, I'm still trying.
Hey, I found something.
Damn?
No.
No, it's not here.
Maybe it was never here.
Maybe we're in the wrong place.
Come on, look at that.
There's got to be something alive in there.
Come on.
Drop your weapon!
Brother Fallou!
I'm not your brother.
You're a disappointing brother,
seduced by the traitor Dixon.
You have your word, you have it.
He has his own, he applies it.
Dixon is faithful only to himself.
He wants to go home.
He wants to go back to his world.
If he takes the boy, what becomes of ours?
Darid wants to save Laurent.
You want to make him a martyr.
Look.
Look at how we have to hide from the hungry ones.
On the rooftops, in the cellars.
Our children, all they've known is fear.
You ready?
And what of their children?
The living coward?
The numbers dwindling, the dead flourishing.
The natural order of things twisted and perverted beyond comprehension.
Some people believe the world has ended.
That God is also dead.
That is why we must find him!
The world must see that God is still here,
and the boy is proof!
That's what faith is?
If you need proof,
you've already lost it.
You made it.
You're going to be okay.
You look okay.
What is that?
Don't worry, we're going to get you out of here.
I'm going to get you out.
Okay.
It's probably just a concussion.
Dehydrated.
I don't think anything's broken.
How many rounds you got left?
One.
We're going to get back to the car.
Got any ideas?
Not any good ones.
What about battery?
You got any battery left?
No, but this thing's not moving.
We just need to crack a window.
No!
Where's Sofia?
Let's just get you out of here.
Finish this water, I'll get you some more, okay?
I don't know about this thing.
You really think this is going to get us home?
You got us here.
How much fuel we need?
Added to what we have,
50 gallons should get us all the way back home.
Alright.
Can I talk to you for a second?
You know you should tell him the truth.
I just want him to get healthy before I break his heart.
Why her though?
Why don't you just lie about something else?
I had to be convincing.
I made up something that I wished was true.
And he lost his son.
Got it.
Why don't you get him ready to fly?
I'll go find some fuel.
Alright?
Yeah?
Can I talk to you for a minute?
Back so soon?
Come on.
I've got a present for you.
Hi.
You alright?
Yeah.
What are you doing here?
We came here looking for you.
Razan came to the camp.
And now Jeanine's dead.
He has some other people behind him.
So I brought him here.
Thank you.
How are you?
What about everyone else?
They alright?
Yeah.
Razan is only interested in one thing.
I need your help.
You can't.
People are going to talk.
I can get you the fuel you need.
Thanks, I appreciate it.
I'm not doing it for you.
Max, load him up with as much ethanol as he can carry.
Not sure we have enough to just give it away.
I'm sorry.
It sounded like you were trying to express an opinion.
Didn't think so.
Faster.
Deal.
So you'll take the boy with you, huh?
What's the plan?
There'll be enough with your neighbor for a while.
Laurent will be safer in America.
At least you guys don't fall for fascists.
The student becomes the master.
I take it she's not coming.
She didn't make it?
No.
There's nothing you can do halfway across the world.
Do you want to talk about it?
No.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
For what?
All of it.
So easy for us to blame ourselves.
During the days I spent waiting for you, I just got to thinking.
How was this trip?
It helped me.
It helped you?
Get past the guilt.
I've been carrying a lot of it.
Coming here with you just forced me to overcome it.
To live again.
You did that for me, Carol.
I'm really sorry I didn't end up better for you.
Well, this one was great.
You should come with us.
I want to stay at the camp.
It's not safe at the camp.
Philippe will find a new place.
And I have friends there.
You can find friends anywhere.
You can find friends where we're going.
There's kids there.
Carol's there. I'm there.
I can't come with you.
Why?
I don't want to.
Explain it to me.
I just can't.
Why not?
Because I don't want you to die.
The sisters, Isabelle, Sylvie, they're all gone.
Because of me.
Everybody, everybody I love dies.
That's not true.
It has nothing to do with you.
Let's go, everyone.
You have to get out of here.
Where's Laurent?
Come on, move.
Come with me, quickly.
Grab his stuff.
You distract them from me, okay?
Need a little push?
No, thank you.
Gilbert?
Are you okay?
It's okay.
There you go.
Lozang, he's here.
You must be the Hope guy.
Where are they?
In the same air.
Is that so?
You believe in miracles, right?
Lozang!
Help me move this.
The truth is hope.
Let's go.
Follow me.
Dixon?
Mr. Caudron?
Yeah.
Hi.
Hi, which way now?
They're coming.
All right, split up.
Come on.
Wait.
They split up.
Gilbert?
Gilbert Fallon.
With me.
The others, follow me.
I need you to do something for me, all right?
Come on, get in.
You stay here until I come back and get you, okay?
What if he didn't come back?
Hey.
When has that ever happened?
You turn it off.
We're gonna get through this, okay?
Fallon!
What's that?
We stay on guard.
Gilbert Fallon.
Over there.
Come on.
Let's go.
This way.
I don't think I can get any cleaner than that.
You should get some more rest.
Well, a little activity would be good for me.
After being stuck in a car for two days.
I'm gonna go.
I really appreciate you making this trip for me.
I'm glad you feel like it was worth it.
The thing is...
I lied.
I didn't come here looking for Sophia.
I came here to look for Daryl.
What are you saying?
Sophia died 12 years ago.
No, you...
You said that...
No, I know what I said.
It's not like that.
What's it like, then?
It's like she never went away.
It's like I never...
let her go because I never forgave myself.
I think you get that.
I know that we share that feeling.
And lately, that feeling's gotten worse.
And when I met you...
I told you what I needed to,
to convince you to help.
So, that makes it all right?
It's not an excuse.
It's just an explanation.
I really hope your therapy is going well.
I know how terrible this is.
It's not just that you lied.
It's the lie itself.
I mean, using your dead daughter
to manipulate me.
What kind of person does that?
A really desperate one, I'm sorry.
I believed in you, don't you get that?
I gave up everything.
I gave up my world, I gave up my home,
my memory of Obby.
But you said before...
You think the end justified the means?
No.
Whatever was happening between us,
every moment of comfort,
or bonding,
or whatever the fuck you want to call it,
it was goddamn fucking meaningless.
The pain was real, the grief...
Oh, come on!
It was all based in a lie.
Your lie to get my fucking plane!
Goddammit!
Don't.
Thank you.
You are always welcome in the damn amount.
Okay.
All right, you ready?
To go where?
To America.
I told you, I'm not going.
Look, I know what you said,
but I think you got it wrong.
You blame yourself.
I get it, that's what kids do.
But you gotta let go of the things that scare you.
Isabel wanted you to go.
I want you to go.
But you gotta make up your own mind.
On what it's gonna be.
Okay.
Good.
Go get your shit, let's go.
It's like the future.
Yep, sure does.
There it is.
You ever seen one of these before?
No, only in books.
Up in the clouds,
we'll be close to Isa and Sylvie.
And my mother.
Yeah, they can watch over us.
How did it go?
Not so good.
You feeling any better?
Who is this?
That's Laurent.
This is Ash.
This is his plane.
Hi.
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
I've never flown in a plane before.
Ash is gonna be the one flying us home.
Yeah, well, one small hitch.
This plane will never get off the ground with all four of us.
So, Paris, we have a problem.